<csw:Record xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:geonet="http://www.fao.org/geonetwork" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows" xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier>47e32c1d-f025-4622-934a-f1b63572609f</dc:identifier>
      <dc:date>2020-10-29T15:49:14Z</dc:date>
      <dc:title>High Resolution Layer: Dominant Leaf Type 2015 (raster 20m), Apr. 2018</dc:title>
      <dc:type>dataset</dc:type>
      <dc:subject>Land cover</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>EEA39</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>forest management</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>landscape alteration</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>land cover</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>land use</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>European</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>Land use</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>Agriculture and food</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>Biodiversity</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>environment</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>imageryBaseMapsEarthCover</dc:subject>
      <dc:format>GeoTIFF</dc:format>
      <dct:abstract>The high resolution forest product consists of three types of (status) products and additional change products. The status products are available for the 2012, 2015 and 2018 reference years: 1. Tree cover density providing level of tree cover density in a range from 0-100%; 2. Dominant leaf type providing information on the dominant leaf type: broadleaved or coniferous; 3. A Forest type product. The forest type product allows to get as close as possible to the FAO forest definition. In its original (20m) resolution it consists of two products: 1) a dominant leaf type product that has a MMU of 0.5 ha, as well as a 10% tree cover density threshold applied, and 2) a support layer that maps, based on the dominant leaf type product, trees under agricultural use and in urban context (derived from CLC and high resolution imperviousness 2009 data). For the final 100m product trees under agricultural use and urban context from the support layer are removed. The high resolution forest change products comprise a simple tree cover density change product for 2012-2015 (% increase or decrease of real tree cover density changes). 
The production of the high resolution forest layers was coordinated by the European Environment Agency (EEA) in the frame of the EU Copernicus programme.</dct:abstract>
      <dc:description>The high resolution forest product consists of three types of (status) products and additional change products. The status products are available for the 2012, 2015 and 2018 reference years: 1. Tree cover density providing level of tree cover density in a range from 0-100%; 2. Dominant leaf type providing information on the dominant leaf type: broadleaved or coniferous; 3. A Forest type product. The forest type product allows to get as close as possible to the FAO forest definition. In its original (20m) resolution it consists of two products: 1) a dominant leaf type product that has a MMU of 0.5 ha, as well as a 10% tree cover density threshold applied, and 2) a support layer that maps, based on the dominant leaf type product, trees under agricultural use and in urban context (derived from CLC and high resolution imperviousness 2009 data). For the final 100m product trees under agricultural use and urban context from the support layer are removed. The high resolution forest change products comprise a simple tree cover density change product for 2012-2015 (% increase or decrease of real tree cover density changes). 
The production of the high resolution forest layers was coordinated by the European Environment Agency (EEA) in the frame of the EU Copernicus programme.</dc:description>
      <dc:rights>otherRestrictions</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights>otherRestrictions</dc:rights>
      <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
      <dc:source>Semi-automatic classification of pre-processed multitemporal High Resolution (HR) satellite image data (Sentinel-2, Landsat 8) with reference year 2015 (+/- 1 year), using supervised and unsupervised elements, leading to scene-based initial land cover classifications. Performing of a time series analysis to extract tree cover and its dominant leaf type (broadleaved and coniferous). Subsequently, interactive manual corrections of the derived tree cover mask have been performed and integrated to a seamless mosaic. Geometric accuracy (positioning scale): Less than one pixel according to ortho-rectified satellite image base delivered by ESA. Thematic accuracy: &gt;90% Overall Accuracy.
Quality assurance follows the ISO9000 standards for Quality Management and comprises of dedicated procedures of ongoing quality checks (QA breakpoints) during implementation of the production chain, in order to keep persistent control over the various stages of production, assure fitness-for-purpose of the end-products and that all quality requirements are fulfilled. Priority has been given to the target thematic accuracies to be achieved by each product, as well as to the issues of product consistency (spatial, thematic, temporal) and homogeneity. Quality Assessment: The quality assessment has been performed according to INSPIRE Data Specifications. The data quality elements considered are:
(i) Completeness,
(ii) Logical Consistency,
(iii) Thematic Accuracy,
(iv) Temporal quality and
(v) Usability.
Each of them (excl. the Thematic Accuracy hereafter) forms a section in the QA/QC Procedures.</dc:source>
      <dc:format>GeoTIFF</dc:format>
      <ows:BoundingBox crs="urn:ogc:def:crs:EPSG:6.6:4326">
        <ows:LowerCorner>27.6375 -31.2684</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>66.5662 -13.4198</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
      <ows:BoundingBox crs="urn:ogc:def:crs:EPSG:6.6:4326">
        <ows:LowerCorner>34.5619 -10.6198</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>71.1855 44.8212</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
      <dc:URI protocol="WWW:LINK-1.0-http--link">https://land.copernicus.eu/pan-european/high-resolution-layers/forests/dominant-leaf-type/status-maps/2015/view</dc:URI>
      <dc:URI protocol="ESRI:REST">https://image.discomap.eea.europa.eu/arcgis/rest/services/GioLandPublic/HRL_DominantLeafType_2015/MapServer</dc:URI>
      <dc:URI protocol="OGC:WMS" name="0" description="Dominant Leaf Type 2015">https://image.discomap.eea.europa.eu/arcgis/services/GioLandPublic/HRL_DominantLeafType_2015/MapServer/WMSServer?service=WMS&amp;request=GetCapabilities&amp;version=1.3.0</dc:URI>
      <dc:URI protocol="image/png">https://sdi.eea.europa.eu/public/catalogue-graphic-overview/47e32c1d-f025-4622-934a-f1b63572609f.png</dc:URI>
    </csw:Record>
    