<csw:Record xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:geonet="http://www.fao.org/geonetwork" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows" xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier>60639d5b-9164-4135-ae93-fb4132bb6d83</dc:identifier>
      <dc:date>2021-05-25T16:56:20.903Z</dc:date>
      <dc:title>High Resolution Layer: Grassland 2018 (raster 10m), Aug. 2020</dc:title>
      <dc:type>dataset</dc:type>
      <dc:subject>Land cover</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>EEA38 (from 2020)</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>United Kingdom</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>land cover</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>land use</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>landscape alteration</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>grassland</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>forest management</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>European</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>Land use</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>environment</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>imageryBaseMapsEarthCover</dc:subject>
      <dc:format>GeoTIFF</dc:format>
      <dct:abstract>The High Resolution Layer (HRL) Grassland 2018 raster product provides a basic land cover classification with 2 thematic classes (grassland / non-grassland) at 10m spatial resolution, covering the EEA38 area and the United Kingdom. The production of the High Resolution grassland layers was coordinated by the European Environment Agency (EEA) in the frame of the EU Copernicus programme.

This is the main High Resolution grassland product. This grassy and non-woody vegetation baseline product includes all kinds of grasslands: managed grassland, semi-natural grassland and natural grassy vegetation. It is a binary status layer for the 2015 reference year mapping grassland and all non-grassland areas in 20m and (aggregated) 100m pixel size and, for the 2018 reference year, in 10m and (aggregated) 100m pixel size.

The dataset for this product is provided as 10 meter rasters in 100 x 100 km tiles (fully conformant with EEA reference grid) grouped according to the EEA38 countries and the United Kingdom.</dct:abstract>
      <dc:description>The High Resolution Layer (HRL) Grassland 2018 raster product provides a basic land cover classification with 2 thematic classes (grassland / non-grassland) at 10m spatial resolution, covering the EEA38 area and the United Kingdom. The production of the High Resolution grassland layers was coordinated by the European Environment Agency (EEA) in the frame of the EU Copernicus programme.

This is the main High Resolution grassland product. This grassy and non-woody vegetation baseline product includes all kinds of grasslands: managed grassland, semi-natural grassland and natural grassy vegetation. It is a binary status layer for the 2015 reference year mapping grassland and all non-grassland areas in 20m and (aggregated) 100m pixel size and, for the 2018 reference year, in 10m and (aggregated) 100m pixel size.

The dataset for this product is provided as 10 meter rasters in 100 x 100 km tiles (fully conformant with EEA reference grid) grouped according to the EEA38 countries and the United Kingdom.</dc:description>
      <dc:rights>otherRestrictions</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights>otherRestrictions</dc:rights>
      <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
      <dc:source>The primary grassland status layer at 10m spatial resolution was produced with a hierarchical spatio-temporal classification of time features derived from Sentinel-2A+B time series (Level-2A data) using a Random Forest (RF) classifier with 200 trees. The selected time window ranges from 01-02-2018 to 30-11-2018, adapted to regional conditions where needed. In total, 137 statistical time features have been calculated and more than 700,000 samples were automatically collected from the LUCAS 2018 database, various CLMS products and additional manual sampling. The final product will be accompanied by a series of expert and reference products (PLOUGH, GRAVPI, Confidence Layer).

Quality assurance follows the ISO 9001:2015 standards for Quality Management and comprises of dedicated procedures of quality checks (QA breakpoints) during implementation of the production chain, in order to keep persistent control over the various stages of production, assure fitness-for-purpose of the end-products and that all quality requirements are fulfilled. Priority has been given to the target thematic accuracy to be achieved by each product, as well as to the issues of product consistency (spatial, thematic, temporal) and homogeneity. Quality Assessment: The quality assessment has been performed according to INSPIRE Data Specifications. The data quality elements considered are: (i) Completeness, (ii) Logical Consistency, (iii) positional accuracy, (iv) Thematic Accuracy, (v) Temporal quality and (vi) Usability.

Geometric accuracy (positioning scale): Less than one pixel (10m) according to ortho-rectified satellite image base (Sentinel-2 Level-2A) delivered by ESA.
Thematic target accuracy: 85% overall accuracy within each bio-geographic region.
Achieved overall accuracy: 95.31% with a 95% confidence level applied. Thematic accuracy has been assessed using a stratified random point sampling approach with 11708 points (area weighted), visually interpreted using VHR_IMAGE_2018 data, Sentinel-2 time series data and complemented by additional data sources like LPIS data sets and Google Earth imagery.

More information about this product can be found in their product specifications here: https://land.copernicus.eu/user-corner/technical-library/hrl-grassland-2018-user-manual.</dc:source>
      <dc:format>GeoTIFF</dc:format>
      <ows:BoundingBox crs="urn:ogc:def:crs:EPSG:6.6:4326">
        <ows:LowerCorner>24.284 -56.506</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>72.665 72.907</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
      <dc:URI protocol="WWW:LINK-1.0-http--link">https://land.copernicus.eu/pan-european/high-resolution-layers/grassland/status-maps/grassland-2018</dc:URI>
      <dc:URI protocol="ESRI:REST">https://image.discomap.eea.europa.eu/arcgis/rest/services/GioLandPublic/HRL_Grassland_2018/ImageServer</dc:URI>
      <dc:URI protocol="OGC:WMS" name="" description="">https://image.discomap.eea.europa.eu/arcgis/services/GioLandPublic/HRL_Grassland_2018/ImageServer/WMSServer?request=GetCapabilities&amp;service=WMS</dc:URI>
      <dc:URI protocol="image/png">https://sdi.eea.europa.eu/public/catalogue-graphic-overview/60639d5b-9164-4135-ae93-fb4132bb6d83.png</dc:URI>
    </csw:Record>
  