<csw:Record xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:geonet="http://www.fao.org/geonetwork" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows" xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier>6aeb0dea-9d8c-42bd-a357-cd859f148929</dc:identifier>
      <dc:date>2022-01-20T15:47:11.9Z</dc:date>
      <dc:title>Riparian Zones Land Cover and Land Use 2012 (vector), Dec. 2021</dc:title>
      <dc:type>dataset</dc:type>
      <dc:subject>Land cover</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>United Kingdom</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>EEA38 (from 2020)</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>tree</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>ecosystem services</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>land cover</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>land use</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>hedge</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>landscape alteration</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>riparian zone</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>European</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>Land use</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>2017 3.6.2</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>environment</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>imageryBaseMapsEarthCover</dc:subject>
      <dc:format>SHP</dc:format>
      <dct:abstract>Riparian zones represent transitional areas occurring between land and freshwater ecosystems, characterised by distinctive hydrology, soil and biotic conditions and strongly influenced by the stream water. They provide a wide range of riparian functions (e.g. chemical filtration, flood control, bank stabilization, aquatic life and riparian wildlife support, etc.) and ecosystem services.

The Riparian Zones products support the objectives of several European legal acts and policy initiatives, such as the EU Biodiversity Strategy to 2020, the Habitats and Birds Directives and the Water Framework Directive.

This metadata refers to the Riparian Zones 2012 Land Cover/Land Use (LC/LU), which LC/LU classification is tailored to the needs of biodiversity monitoring in a variable buffer zone of selected rivers (Strahler levels 2-9 derived from EU-Hydro) for the reference year 2012. LC/LU is extracted from Very High Resolution (VHR) satellite data and other available data in a buffer zone of selected rivers for supporting biodiversity monitoring and mapping and assessment of ecosystems and their services. The class definitions follow the pre-defined nomenclature on the basis of Mapping and Assessment of Ecosystems and their Services (MAES) typology of ecosystems (Level 1 to Level 4) and CORINE Land Cover. The classification provides 55 distinct thematic classes with a Minimum Mapping Unit (MMU) of 0.5 ha and a Minimum Mapping Width (MMW) of 10 m. The nomenclature has been revised in 2020 with the aim to harmonize the products of the local components (mainly Riparian Zones and NATURA 2000 products) while maintaining user requirements for both products. A revised version of the Riparian Zones 2012 has been subsequently released in December 2021, together with the reference year 2018.  

The production of the Riparian Zones products was coordinated by the European Environment Agency in the frame of the EU Copernicus programme.</dct:abstract>
      <dc:description>Riparian zones represent transitional areas occurring between land and freshwater ecosystems, characterised by distinctive hydrology, soil and biotic conditions and strongly influenced by the stream water. They provide a wide range of riparian functions (e.g. chemical filtration, flood control, bank stabilization, aquatic life and riparian wildlife support, etc.) and ecosystem services.

The Riparian Zones products support the objectives of several European legal acts and policy initiatives, such as the EU Biodiversity Strategy to 2020, the Habitats and Birds Directives and the Water Framework Directive.

This metadata refers to the Riparian Zones 2012 Land Cover/Land Use (LC/LU), which LC/LU classification is tailored to the needs of biodiversity monitoring in a variable buffer zone of selected rivers (Strahler levels 2-9 derived from EU-Hydro) for the reference year 2012. LC/LU is extracted from Very High Resolution (VHR) satellite data and other available data in a buffer zone of selected rivers for supporting biodiversity monitoring and mapping and assessment of ecosystems and their services. The class definitions follow the pre-defined nomenclature on the basis of Mapping and Assessment of Ecosystems and their Services (MAES) typology of ecosystems (Level 1 to Level 4) and CORINE Land Cover. The classification provides 55 distinct thematic classes with a Minimum Mapping Unit (MMU) of 0.5 ha and a Minimum Mapping Width (MMW) of 10 m. The nomenclature has been revised in 2020 with the aim to harmonize the products of the local components (mainly Riparian Zones and NATURA 2000 products) while maintaining user requirements for both products. A revised version of the Riparian Zones 2012 has been subsequently released in December 2021, together with the reference year 2018.  

The production of the Riparian Zones products was coordinated by the European Environment Agency in the frame of the EU Copernicus programme.</dc:description>
      <dc:rights>otherRestrictions</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights>otherRestrictions</dc:rights>
      <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
      <dc:source>Computer assisted visual refinement of the status 2012 data based on the precursor LC/LU product for reference year 2012. The main dataset for visual image interpretation was the DWH_MG2b_CORE_03 dataset (Optical VHR2 coverage over EU 2011-2013 and Riparian zones), mainly consisting of 1.5m VHR2 SPOT-6 and 2.5m VHR2 SPOT-5 HRG and 2m Pleiades satellite data. Subsequently, intersection of classification results with additional data (Urban Atlas 2012) was performed.

The first version of the LC/LU dataset (produced in 2015 under the GMES Initial Operations phase) related to rivers pertaining to Strahler levels 3 to 8. The pre-defined nomenclature on the basis of the MAES typology of ecosystems was composed of 79 classes. In 2017, to allow for a harmonisation of the nomenclatures applied to the different local component products (Costal Zones and N2K), a revision of the nomenclature was undertaken which resulted in a reduction of classes (down to 56). A LC/LU dataset covering rivers pertaining to Strahler level 2 was produced applying the new nomenclature and the previous dataset (covering Strahler levels 3 to 8) was re-coded to the new nomenclature. The two datasets were merged together and a harmonised dataset covering rivers pertaining to Strahler levels 2 to 9 was produced. In 2020 an additional exercise of harmonisation of the nomenclature (re-naming and re-coding) took place. The current LC/LU layer differentiates 55 thematic LC/LU classes covering Strahler levels 2 to 9 for the reference year 2012.

Positional Accuracy: less than 5 m (according to geo-location accuracy of satellite imagery delivered by ESA: less than 5m RMSE). Thematic accuracy (area-corrected Overall Accuracy) &#8805; 85% (at CODE_4 level). Accuracy Assessment approach: Stratified Random Point Sampling. Interpretation of sampling points has been performed on the best available reference data.</dc:source>
      <dc:format>SHP</dc:format>
      <ows:BoundingBox crs="urn:ogc:def:crs:EPSG:6.6:4326">
        <ows:LowerCorner>27.735635 -31.233429</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>71.141304 44.819104</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
      <dc:URI protocol="WWW:LINK-1.0-http--link">https://land.copernicus.eu/local/riparian-zones/riparian-zones-2012</dc:URI>
      <dc:URI protocol="OGC:WMS" description="Riparian Zones 2012 LCLU">https://copernicus.discomap.eea.europa.eu/arcgis/services/RiparianZones/RZ_2012/MapServer/WMSServer?request=GetCapabilities&amp;service=WMS</dc:URI>
      <dc:URI protocol="ESRI:REST">https://copernicus.discomap.eea.europa.eu/arcgis/rest/services/RiparianZones/RZ_2012/MapServer</dc:URI>
      <dc:URI protocol="image/png">https://sdi.eea.europa.eu/public/catalogue-graphic-overview/6aeb0dea-9d8c-42bd-a357-cd859f148929.png</dc:URI>
    </csw:Record>
    