<csw:Record xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:geonet="http://www.fao.org/geonetwork" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows" xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier>a0925bc0-d3d8-49af-ba9d-c4f1cf2b654d</dc:identifier>
      <dc:date>2020-10-29T09:25:55Z</dc:date>
      <dc:title>High Resolution Layer: Grassland Change 2015-2018 (raster 20m), Oct. 2020</dc:title>
      <dc:type>dataset</dc:type>
      <dc:subject>Land cover</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>EEA38 (from 2020)</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>United Kingdom</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>land cover</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>forest management</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>land use</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>landscape alteration</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>European</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>Land use</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>environment</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>imageryBaseMapsEarthCover</dc:subject>
      <dc:format>GeoTIFF</dc:format>
      <dct:abstract>The High Resolution Layer (HRL) Grassland Change 2015-2018 raster product at 20m resolution provides information on changes in grassland vegetation cover between the reference years 2015 and 2018. The thematic classes indicate all non-grassland areas, grassland gain and grassland loss, unchanged grassland in both years and unverified grassland gain and loss areas for the pan-European area of EEA38 and the United Kingdom. The production of the High Resolution grassland layers was coordinated by the European Environment Agency (EEA) in the frame of the EU Copernicus programme.
This dataset is provided as 20 meter rasters in 100 x 100 km tiles grouped according to the EEA38 countries and the United Kingdom (fully conformant with the EEA reference grid).
The HRL Grassland layer is the main High Resolution grassland product. This grassy and non-woody vegetation baseline product includes all kinds of grasslands: managed grassland, semi-natural grassland and natural grassy vegetation. It is a binary status layer for the 2015 reference year mapping grassland and all non-grassland areas in 20m and (aggregated) 100m pixel size and, for the 2018 reference year, in 10m and (aggregated) 100m pixel size.</dct:abstract>
      <dc:description>The High Resolution Layer (HRL) Grassland Change 2015-2018 raster product at 20m resolution provides information on changes in grassland vegetation cover between the reference years 2015 and 2018. The thematic classes indicate all non-grassland areas, grassland gain and grassland loss, unchanged grassland in both years and unverified grassland gain and loss areas for the pan-European area of EEA38 and the United Kingdom. The production of the High Resolution grassland layers was coordinated by the European Environment Agency (EEA) in the frame of the EU Copernicus programme.
This dataset is provided as 20 meter rasters in 100 x 100 km tiles grouped according to the EEA38 countries and the United Kingdom (fully conformant with the EEA reference grid).
The HRL Grassland layer is the main High Resolution grassland product. This grassy and non-woody vegetation baseline product includes all kinds of grasslands: managed grassland, semi-natural grassland and natural grassy vegetation. It is a binary status layer for the 2015 reference year mapping grassland and all non-grassland areas in 20m and (aggregated) 100m pixel size and, for the 2018 reference year, in 10m and (aggregated) 100m pixel size.</dc:description>
      <dc:rights>otherRestrictions</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights>otherRestrictions</dc:rights>
      <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
      <dc:source>The Grassland Change Layer 2015-2018 at 20m spatial resolution is derived from the primary Pan-European Grassland Status Layers of the reference years 2015 (HRL GRA at 20m resolution) and 2018 (HRL GRA at 10m spatial resolution) and covers the area of EEA38 and the United Kingdom. The GRA Change Layer is the first of its kind indicating changes in grassland vegetation cover in five thematic classes. The production workflow consists of a map-to-map comparison of both years and takes adequate time features of both years as well as ploughing information from PLOUGH 2015 and 2018 back to the year 2010 into account.

Due to substantial transformations concerning resolution (20m to 10m), significantly enhanced data availability and therefore a refined technical approach, differences between the reference years of 2015 and 2018 are not always illustrating real changes in grassland vegetation cover but are sometimes technically induced. Areas differing in the years 2015 and 2018 that could not be verified as real change by the workflow are therefore labelled as unverified gain or loss areas.

Geometric accuracy (positioning scale): Less than one pixel (10m) according to ortho-rectified satellite image base (Sentinel-2 Level-2A) delivered by ESA.

Thematic target accuracy: The thematic accuracy has been assessed on the primary pan-European Change product and refers to classes 1-gain, 2-loss, 10-unchanged grassland in both years an 0-all non-grassland areas. Unverified areas are not part of the validation process. The unweighted overall accuracy is 88,97%. The weighted overall accuracy is 99,30% and considers the relative importance of all classes.

More information about this product can be found in their product specifications here: https://land.copernicus.eu/user-corner/technical-library/hrl-grassland-2018-user-manual.</dc:source>
      <dc:format>GeoTIFF</dc:format>
      <ows:BoundingBox crs="urn:ogc:def:crs:EPSG:6.6:4326">
        <ows:LowerCorner>24.284 -56.506</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>72.665 72.907</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
      <dc:URI protocol="WWW:LINK-1.0-http--link" name="Download (requires authentication)">https://land.copernicus.eu/pan-european/high-resolution-layers/grassland/change-maps/grassland-change-2015-2018?tab=download</dc:URI>
      <dc:URI protocol="ESRI:REST">https://image.discomap.eea.europa.eu/arcgis/rest/services/GioLandPublic/HRL_GrasslandChange_15_18/ImageServer</dc:URI>
      <dc:URI protocol="OGC:WMS" name="" description="">https://image.discomap.eea.europa.eu/arcgis/services/GioLandPublic/HRL_GrasslandChange_15_18/ImageServer/WMSServer?request=GetCapabilities&amp;service=WMS</dc:URI>
      <dc:URI protocol="image/png">https://sdi.eea.europa.eu/public/catalogue-graphic-overview/a0925bc0-d3d8-49af-ba9d-c4f1cf2b654d.png</dc:URI>
    </csw:Record>
    