<csw:Record xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:geonet="http://www.fao.org/geonetwork" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows" xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier>f6bbd22c-52e5-4e47-9b09-943415fcb52e</dc:identifier>
      <dc:date>2021-06-29T09:17:40.919Z</dc:date>
      <dc:title>High Resolution Layer: Water and Wetness 2018 (raster 100m), Nov. 2020</dc:title>
      <dc:type>dataset</dc:type>
      <dc:subject>Land cover</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>EEA38 (from 2020)</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>United Kingdom</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>water</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>land cover</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>land use</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>forest management</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>landscape alteration</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>European</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>Land use</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>2018 3.6.1</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>environment</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>imageryBaseMapsEarthCover</dc:subject>
      <dc:format>GeoTIFF</dc:format>
      <dct:abstract>The Copernicus High Resolution Layer Water and Wetness (WAW) 2018 is a thematic product showing the occurrence of water and wet surfaces over the period from 2012 to 2018 for the EEA38 area and the United Kingdom. This metadata refers to the 100 meter aggregate raster, provided as a full EEA38 and United Kingdom mosaic (fully conformant to with the EEA reference grid). The production of the High Resolution Water and Wetness layers was coordinated by the European Environment Agency (EEA) in the frame of the EU Copernicus programme

Two Water and Wetness products are available:
- The main Water and Wetness (WAW) product, with defined classes of (1) permanent water, (2) temporary water, (3) permanent wetness and (4) temporary wetness.
- The additional expert product: Water and Wetness Probability Index (WWPI).
The products show the occurrence of water and indicate the degree of wetness in a physical sense, assessed independently of the actual vegetation cover and are thus not limited to a specific land cover class and their relative frequencies.</dct:abstract>
      <dc:description>The Copernicus High Resolution Layer Water and Wetness (WAW) 2018 is a thematic product showing the occurrence of water and wet surfaces over the period from 2012 to 2018 for the EEA38 area and the United Kingdom. This metadata refers to the 100 meter aggregate raster, provided as a full EEA38 and United Kingdom mosaic (fully conformant to with the EEA reference grid). The production of the High Resolution Water and Wetness layers was coordinated by the European Environment Agency (EEA) in the frame of the EU Copernicus programme

Two Water and Wetness products are available:
- The main Water and Wetness (WAW) product, with defined classes of (1) permanent water, (2) temporary water, (3) permanent wetness and (4) temporary wetness.
- The additional expert product: Water and Wetness Probability Index (WWPI).
The products show the occurrence of water and indicate the degree of wetness in a physical sense, assessed independently of the actual vegetation cover and are thus not limited to a specific land cover class and their relative frequencies.</dc:description>
      <dc:rights>otherRestrictions</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights>otherRestrictions</dc:rights>
      <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
      <dc:source>The 10m classified Water and Wetness layer is aggregated to 100m for the complete European LAEA layer according to the procedure described as follows: for the aggregation of the 10m classified product to a 100m raster in a concise way, all underlying 10m cells are considered. A majority rule is applied to ensure that the most appropriate class value is given to the 100m cell, 
considering all underlying 100 pixels that are covered by the 100m raster cell. The 100m cell receives the code of the majority of 10m pixels, under consideration of the fraction of valid and un-valid pixels and equality. More information about the aggregation methodology and about the product in general can be found here: https://land.copernicus.eu/user-corner/technical-library/hrl-water-and-wetness-2018-user-manual. 

Quality assurance follows the ISO9000 standards for Quality Management and comprises of dedicated procedures of on-going quality checks (QA breakpoints) during implementation of the production chain, in order to keep persistent control over the various stages of production, assure fitness-for-purpose of the end-products and that all quality requirements are fulfilled. Priority will be given to the target thematic accuracies to be achieved by each product, as well as to the issues of product consistency (spatial, thematic, temporal) and homogeneity.
Quality Assessment: The quality assessment has been performed according to INSPIRE Data Specifications. The data quality elements considered are:
(i) Completeness,
(ii) Logical Consistency,
(iii) Thematic Accuracy,
(iv) Temporal quality and (v) Usability.
Each of them (excl. the Thematic Accuracy hereafter) forms a section in the QA/QC Procedures.</dc:source>
      <dc:format>GeoTIFF</dc:format>
      <ows:BoundingBox crs="urn:ogc:def:crs:EPSG:6.6:4326">
        <ows:LowerCorner>27.642 -31.285</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>71.165 44.807</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
      <dc:URI protocol="WWW:LINK-1.0-http--link">https://land.copernicus.eu/pan-european/high-resolution-layers/water-wetness/status-maps/water-wetness-2018</dc:URI>
      <dc:URI protocol="image/png">https://sdi.eea.europa.eu/public/catalogue-graphic-overview/f6bbd22c-52e5-4e47-9b09-943415fcb52e.png</dc:URI>
    </csw:Record>
    