<csw:Record xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EO:DEM:DAT:COP-DEM_GLO-30-DGED__2022_1</dc:identifier>
      <dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">COPERNICUS Digital Elevation Model (DEM) 30 meters</dc:title>
      <dc:type xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">dataset</dc:type>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">elevation</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">earth observation</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">satellite imagery</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">MOOD-H2020</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">World</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Elevation</dc:subject>
      <dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">GeoTIFF</dc:format>
      <dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">DTED</dc:format>
      <dct:abstract xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">The Copernicus DEM is a Digital Surface Model (DSM) which represents the surface of the Earth including buildings, infrastructure and vegetation. 
We provide two instances of Copernicus DEM named GLO-30 Public and GLO-90. GLO-30 provides worldwide coverage at 30 meters. 
Note that ocean areas do not have tiles, there one can assume height values equal to zero. 
Data is provided as Cloud Optimized GeoTIFFs. 
Several releases are currently available for all Copernicus DEM instances, only the last one is provided as 2022 release. 
A full collection of tiles can be found via FTP and PANDA Catalogue under dataset names marked with &#8220;2022_1&#8221;.</dct:abstract>
      <dct:spatial xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">EPSG::WGS 84 (EPSG:4326)</dct:spatial>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">according to license</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">GLO-30 Public and GLO-90 are available on a free basis for the general public under the terms and conditions of the Licence found here: https://spacedata.copernicus.eu/documents/20126/0/CSCDA_ESA_Mission-specific+Annex.pdf

The GLO-90 dataset is available worldwide with a free license. The GLO-30 dataset (dataset ID: COP-DEM_GLO-30-DTED_PUBLIC and COP-DEM_GLO-30-DGED_PUBLIC) is available worldwide with a free license with the exception of two countries, reported in a dedicated list (https://spacedata.copernicus.eu/documents/20126/0/Non-released-tiles_GLO-30_PUBLIC_Dec.xlsx/bcdd6cef-6379-4890-de8f-788daf41dce8?t=1608549440765).

Attribution:
For Primary Products:
"&#169; DLR e.V. (2014-2018)  and  &#169;  Airbus  Defence  and Space GmbH (year  of  production) provided under COPERNICUS by the European Union and ESA; all rights reserved."

For Altered Products:
"produced using products &#169; DLR e.V. (2014-2018) and &#169; Airbus Defence and Space GmbH (yearofproduction) provided under COPERNICUS by the European Union and ESA, all rights reserved&#8221;

Any publication whatsoever resulting from work carried out using Primary Products/ Altered Products shall contain the following sentence: &#8220;EO  data  provided  under  COPERNICUS  by  the  European  Union and  ESA.&#8221;

When  communicating  to  the  General  Public  or  distributing  the Copernicus  WorldDEM&#8482;-90,  the  User  shall inform the General Public of the source by using the following notice:
"&#169; DLR e.V. 2010-2014 and &#169; Airbus Defence and Space GmbH 2014-2018 provided under COPERNICUS by the European Union and ESA; all rights reserved".

Where  the Copernicus  WorldDEM&#8482;-90  data have  been  adapted  or  modified,  the  User  shall  provide the following notice:
"produced using Copernicus WorldDEM&#8482;-90 &#169; DLR e.V. 2010-2014 and &#169; Airbus Defence and Space GmbH 2014-2018 provided under COPERNICUS by the European Union and ESA; all rights reserved&#8221;.</dc:rights>
      <dct:accessRights xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">otherRestrictions</dct:accessRights>
      <ows:BoundingBox xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows">
        <ows:LowerCorner>-180.00 -90.00</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>180.00 90.00</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
    </csw:Record>
    