<csw:Record xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EO:ECMWF:DAT:SIS_EUROPEAN_WIND_STORM_INDICATORS</dc:identifier>
      <dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Winter windstorm indicators for Europe from 1979 to 2021 derived from reanalysis</dc:title>
      <dc:type xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">dataset</dc:type>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Meteorological geographical features</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Spatial coverage: Europe</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Variable domain: Atmosphere (surface)</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Temporal coverage: Past</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Product type: Reanalysis</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Provider: Copernicus C3S</dc:subject>
      <dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">netcdf</dc:format>
      <dct:abstract xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">This dataset provides climatological indicators on European winter windstorms and their economic impact derived from ERA5 reanalysis. Also provided are risk indicators from a synthetically derived set of physically realistic windstorm events based on modelled climatic conditions. The primary users include the insurance sector, reinsurers and insurance industry service providers in response to their requirements for a catalogue of historic windstorm events within Europe. It is important for this sector to be able to characterise the temporal and geographic distribution of potentially destructive windstorm events over Europe. These data can also support sectors such as energy, transport, civil engineering and government.
The indicators available in this dataset are categorised as follows: 


Windstorm tracks &#8211; the spatial track centred on the location of maximum relative vorticity above a threshold defining a windstorm as it moves over the North Atlantic Ocean and Europe. 


Windstorm footprints &#8211; the maximum wind speed of gusts for each grid point of the domain during the passage of the storm over a period of 72-hours since the selected storm is first identified.


Summary indicators (Tier 1) &#8211; uses the windstorm tracks and maximum 10m wind speed to produce annual and decadal summary statistics for the land regions in Europe.


Loss and risk indicators (Tier 3) &#8211; describing the socio-economic impact of windstorms for various land cover and building types in Europe.


This dataset was produced on behalf of the Copernicus Climate Change Service.</dct:abstract>
      <dct:spatial xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">::EPSG:4326</dct:spatial>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/api/v2/terms/static/licence-to-use-copernicus-products.pdf</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Content accessible through the CDS may only be used under the terms of the licenses attributed to each particular resource.</dc:rights>
      <dct:accessRights xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">licence</dct:accessRights>
      <ows:BoundingBox xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows">
        <ows:LowerCorner>-180 -90</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>180 90</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
    </csw:Record>
    