<csw:Record xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EO:ECMWF:DAT:SATELLITE_EARTH_RADIATION_BUDGET</dc:identifier>
      <dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Earth's radiation budget from 1979 to present derived from satellite observations</dc:title>
      <dc:type xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">dataset</dc:type>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Atmospheric conditions</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Product type: Satellite observations</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Temporal coverage: Past</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Temporal coverage: Present</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Variable domain: Atmosphere (upper air)</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Spatial coverage: Global</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Provider: Copernicus C3S</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Provider: ESA CCI</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Provider: RMIB</dc:subject>
      <dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">NetCDF, Ascii</dc:format>
      <dct:abstract xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">The Earth&#8217;s Radiation Budget (ERB) represents the overall balance between incoming and outgoing radiant energy at the Earth&#8217;s Top-of-the-Atmosphere. This Essential Climate Variable (ECV) is the primary forcing of the climate system and is therefore a fundamental quantity to be monitored to understand the Earth&#8217;s climate and its variability. The ERB comprises the quantification of the incoming radiation from the Sun and the outgoing reflected shortwave and emitted longwave radiation.
The ERB represents the balance between incoming, predominantly solar, radiation and outgoing radiation as either reflected solar radiation or thermal radiation emitted by the Earth system. The Earth is in a state of dynamic radiative balance, energy arriving from the Sun is balanced by outgoing radiation from the top-of-the-atmosphere. Changes in the Earth&#8217;s surface and atmosphere (including cloud amount and properties, and concentrations of greenhouse gases) will alter the radiative balance of the Earth system and change the balance and distribution of outgoing thermal radiation and reflected solar radiation. Aside from the elevation (height) of the sun above the horizon, the largest factor controlling the variability in the Earth radiation budget is cloud cover; the fraction of cloud cover, their height and opacity all impact on both the reflected solar and outgoing infrared radiation. Thus, knowledge of cloud properties, along with atmospheric composition and surface properties, allows the earth radiation budget to be computed. 
This catalogue entry comprises data from  a number of sources which are summarised in the following sections.</dct:abstract>
      <dct:spatial xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">::EPSG:4326</dct:spatial>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/api/v2/terms/static/licence-to-use-copernicus-products.pdf</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Content accessible through the CDS may only be used under the terms of the licenses attributed to each particular resource.</dc:rights>
      <dct:accessRights xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">licence</dct:accessRights>
      <ows:BoundingBox xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows">
        <ows:LowerCorner>-180 -90</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>180 90</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
    </csw:Record>
    