<csw:Record xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EO:ECMWF:DAT:REANALYSIS_ERA5_LAND_MONTHLY_MEANS</dc:identifier>
      <dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">ERA5-Land monthly averaged data from 1950 to present</dc:title>
      <dc:type xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">dataset</dc:type>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Land conditions</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Product type: Reanalysis</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Spatial coverage: Global</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Temporal coverage: Past</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Variable domain: Land (hydrology)</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Variable domain: Land (physics)</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Variable domain: Land (biosphere)</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Provider: Copernicus C3S</dc:subject>
      <dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">grib</dc:format>
      <dct:abstract xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">ERA5-Land is a reanalysis dataset providing a consistent view of the evolution of land variables over several decades at an enhanced resolution compared to ERA5. ERA5-Land has been produced by replaying the land component of the ECMWF ERA5 climate reanalysis. Reanalysis combines model data with observations from across the world into a globally complete and consistent dataset using the laws of physics. Reanalysis produces data that goes several decades back in time, providing an accurate description of the climate of the past.
ERA5-Land provides a consistent view of the water and energy cycles at surface level during several decades.
It contains a detailed record from 1950 onwards, with a temporal resolution of 1 hour. The native spatial resolution of the ERA5-Land reanalysis dataset is 9km on a reduced Gaussian grid (TCo1279). The data in the CDS has been regridded to a regular lat-lon grid of 0.1x0.1 degrees.
The data presented here is a post-processed subset of the full ERA5-Land dataset. Monthly-mean averages have been pre-calculated to facilitate many applications requiring easy and fast access to the data, when sub-monthly fields are not required.
Hourly fields can be found in the ERA5-Land hourly fields CDS page. Documentation can be found in the online ERA5-Land documentation.

Variables in the dataset/application are:
10m u-component of wind, 10m v-component of wind, 2m dewpoint temperature, 2m temperature, Evaporation from bare soil, Evaporation from open water surfaces excluding oceans, Evaporation from the top of canopy, Evaporation from vegetation transpiration, Forecast albedo, Lake bottom temperature, Lake ice depth, Lake ice temperature, Lake mix-layer depth, Lake mix-layer temperature, Lake shape factor, Lake total layer temperature, Leaf area index, high vegetation, Leaf area index, low vegetation, Potential evaporation, Runoff, Skin reservoir content, Skin temperature, Snow albedo, Snow cover, Snow density, Snow depth, Snow depth water equivalent, Snow evaporation, Snowfall, Snowmelt, Soil temperature level 1, Soil temperature level 2, Soil temperature level 3, Soil temperature level 4, Sub-surface runoff, Surface latent heat flux, Surface net solar radiation, Surface net thermal radiation, Surface pressure, Surface runoff, Surface sensible heat flux, Surface solar radiation downwards, Surface thermal radiation downwards, Temperature of snow layer, Total evaporation, Total precipitation, Volumetric soil water layer 1, Volumetric soil water layer 2, Volumetric soil water layer 3, Volumetric soil water layer 4</dct:abstract>
      <dct:spatial xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">::EPSG:4326</dct:spatial>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/api/v2/terms/static/20180314_Copernicus_License_V1.1.pdf</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Content accessible through the CDS may only be used under the terms of the licenses attributed to each particular resource.</dc:rights>
      <dct:accessRights xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">licence</dct:accessRights>
      <ows:BoundingBox xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows">
        <ows:LowerCorner>-180 -90</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>180 90</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
    </csw:Record>
    