<csw:Record xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EO:ECMWF:DAT:SIS_EUROPEAN_RISK_FLOOD_INDICATORS</dc:identifier>
      <dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Flood risk indicators for European cities from 1989 to 2018</dc:title>
      <dc:type xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">dataset</dc:type>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Meteorological geographical features</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sector: Disaster risk reduction</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sector: Water management</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Spatial coverage: Europe</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Variable domain: Land (hydrology)</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Temporal coverage: Past</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Product type: Climate indices</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Provider: Copernicus C3S</dc:subject>
      <dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">netcdf</dc:format>
      <dct:abstract xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">The dataset presents indicators to evaluate the spatial distribution of flood risk in terms of hazards and direct damages. It is provided as a high-resolution product focused on 20 European cities that were identified as vulnerable to urban pluvial flooding by experts and practitioners from government agencies and Civil Protection. The dataset combines a high-resolution, probabilistic, description of extreme precipitation, exposure datasets and damage/vulnerability models into a comprehensive pluvial flood risk assessment for cities across Europe for the current climate. It allows city stakeholders to exploit flood risk analysis over the city.
The dataset is derived from data available on the Climate Data Store and the Copernicus Land Monitoring Service (CLMS). The former includes ERA5 reanalysis data, dynamically downscaled to 2km x 2km grid with the regional climate model COSMO-CLM and accounting for urban parameterization in order to reach the spatial and temporal resolution suitable for pluvial flood analysis at a city scale. This downscaled product is used for deriving hourly precipitation input at prescribed recurrence intervals that, in combination with supporting digital elevation models (DEM) from the CLMS, is used to feed hazard and damage models.
This dataset was produced on behalf of the Copernicus Climate Change Service.

Variables in the dataset/application are:
Expected damage, Urban depression, Water depth, Water mask</dct:abstract>
      <dct:spatial xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">::EPSG:4326</dct:spatial>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/api/v2/terms/static/licence-to-use-copernicus-products.pdf</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Content accessible through the CDS may only be used under the terms of the licenses attributed to each particular resource.</dc:rights>
      <dct:accessRights xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">licence</dct:accessRights>
      <ows:BoundingBox xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows">
        <ows:LowerCorner>-180 -90</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>180 90</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
    </csw:Record>
    