<csw:Record xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EO:ECMWF:DAT:SATELLITE_LAND_COVER</dc:identifier>
      <dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Land cover classification gridded maps from 1992 to present derived from satellite observations</dc:title>
      <dc:type xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">dataset</dc:type>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Land cover</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Product type: Satellite observations</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Spatial coverage: Global</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Variable domain: Land (biosphere)</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Temporal coverage: Past</dc:subject>
      <dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">netcdf</dc:format>
      <dct:abstract xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">This dataset provides global maps describing the land surface into 22 classes, which have been defined using the United Nations Food and Agriculture Organization&#8217;s (UN FAO) Land Cover Classification System (LCCS). In addition to the land cover  (LC) maps, four quality flags are produced to document the reliability of the classification and change detection. 
In order to ensure continuity, these land cover maps are consistent with the series of global annual LC maps from the 1990s to 2015 produced by the European Space Agency (ESA) Climate Change Initiative (CCI), which are also available on the ESA CCI LC viewer.
To produce this dataset, the entire  Medium Resolution Imaging Spectrometer (MERIS) Full and Reduced Resolution  archive from 2003 to 2012 was first classified into a unique 10-year baseline LC map. This is then back- and up-dated using change detected from (i) Advanced Very-High-Resolution Radiometer (AVHRR) time series from 1992 to 1999, (ii) SPOT-Vegetation (SPOT-VGT) time series from 1998 to 2012 and (iii) PROBA-Vegetation (PROBA-V) and Sentinel-3 OLCI (S3 OLCI) time series from 2013.
Beyond the climate-modelling communities, this dataset&#8217;s long-term consistency, yearly updates, and high thematic detail on a global scale have made it attractive for a multitude of applications such as land accounting, forest monitoring and desertification, in addition to scientific research.

Variables in the dataset/application are:
Change count, Current pixel state, Land cover class, Observation count, Processed flag</dct:abstract>
      <dct:spatial xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">::EPSG:4326</dct:spatial>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/api/v2/terms/static/satellite-land-cover.pdf</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Content accessible through the CDS may only be used under the terms of the licenses attributed to each particular resource.</dc:rights>
      <dct:accessRights xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">licence</dct:accessRights>
      <ows:BoundingBox xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows">
        <ows:LowerCorner>-180 -90</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>180 90</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
    </csw:Record>
    