<csw:Record xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EO:ECMWF:DAT:SATELLITE_PRECIPITATION</dc:identifier>
      <dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Precipitation monthly and daily gridded data from 1979 to present derived from satellite measurements</dc:title>
      <dc:type xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">dataset</dc:type>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Meteorological geographical features</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Product type: Satellite observations</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Spatial coverage: Global</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Variable domain: Land (hydrology)</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Variable domain: Atmosphere (surface)</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Temporal coverage: Past</dc:subject>
      <dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">netcdf</dc:format>
      <dct:abstract xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">The analysis of the Global Precipitation Climatology Project (GPCP) provides global estimates of precipitation as monthly means since 1979 (GPCP monthly v2.3) and as daily means since 1996 (GPCP daily v1.3), based on estimates using microwave imagers on polar-orbiting satellites and infrared imagers on geostationary satellites. The monthly product also includes information from rain-gauge observations analyzed by the Global Precipitation Climatology Centre (GPCC). The GPCP daily product is tied to GPCC indirectly via its calibration with the GPCP monthly product.
Within the hydrological cycle, precipitation is the main component of water transport from the atmosphere to the Earth&#8217;s surface. Precipitation varies strongly, depending on geographical location, season, synopsis, and other meteorological factors. The supply with freshwater through precipitation is vital for many subsystems of the climate and the environment, but there are also hazards related to extensive precipitation or the lack of precipitation.
This dataset is brokered from the GPCP: see licence text on the right.

Variables in the dataset/application are:
Precipitation</dct:abstract>
      <dct:spatial xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">::EPSG:4326</dct:spatial>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/api/v2/terms/static/global-precipitation-climatology-project.pdf</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Content accessible through the CDS may only be used under the terms of the licenses attributed to each particular resource.</dc:rights>
      <dct:accessRights xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">licence</dct:accessRights>
      <ows:BoundingBox xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows">
        <ows:LowerCorner>-180 -90</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>180 90</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
    </csw:Record>
  