<csw:Record xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EO:ECMWF:DAT:SIS_WATER_LEVEL_CHANGE_INDICATORS</dc:identifier>
      <dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Water level change indicators for the European coast from 1977 to 2100 derived from climate projections</dc:title>
      <dc:type xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">dataset</dc:type>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Hydrography</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sector: Water management</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sector: Disaster risk reduction</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Product type: Climate projections</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Spatial coverage: Europe</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Variable domain: Ocean (physics)</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Temporal coverage: Past</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Temporal coverage: Present</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Temporal coverage: Future</dc:subject>
      <dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">netcdf</dc:format>
      <dct:abstract xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">The dataset presents extreme-value, return period, and percentile indicators for coastal sea levels in a European-wide domain. The indicators are computed from tidal dynamics, storm surge and sea level rise data based upon past observational data and future climate projections. This dataset provides an understanding of the European coastal hydrodynamics under the impact of climate change. It provides added value for various coastal sectors and studies such as port, shipping, and coastal management.
To compute these indicators, the Deltares Global Tide and Surge Model (GTSM) version 3.0 is used together with regional climate forcing and sea level rise initial conditions. The regional climate forcing employed is the HIRHAM5 model from the Danish Meteorological Institute (DMI), a member of the EURO-CORDEX climate model ensemble, which is downscaled from the global climate model EC-EARTH. By using a regional climate model and a high-resolution forcing field, GTSM is able to produce a more consistent and high quality dataset. In order to assess the impact of climate change, the GTSM model is run for three different climate scenarios: the present climate (labelled 'historical'), and two Representative Concentration Pathway (RCP) scenarios that correspond to an optimistic emission scenario where emissions start declining beyond 2040 (RCP4.5) and a pessimistic scenario where emissions continue to rise throughout the century often called the business-as-usual scenario (RCP8.5). Given that the projections of these climate scenarios are based on a single combination of the regional and global climate models, users of these data should take in consideration that there is an inevitable underestimation of the uncertainty associated with this dataset. In addition to the climate scenarios, a reanalysis dataset is computed by forcing GTSM with ERA5 reanalysis. This provides recent historical water-levels that can be used to look at specific (extreme) events in the past.
This dataset was produced on behalf of the Copernicus Climate Change Service.

Variables in the dataset/application are:
Annual highest high water, Annual lowest low water, Annual mean highest high water, Annual mean lowest low water, Epoch-mean highest high water, Epoch-mean lowest low water, Highest astronomical tide, Lowest astronomical tide, Mean sea level, Surge level for different percentiles, Surge level for different return periods, Tidal range, Total water level for different percentiles, Total water level for different return periods</dct:abstract>
      <dct:spatial xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">::EPSG:4326</dct:spatial>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/api/v2/terms/static/20191121_Copernicus_License_V1.2.pdf</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Content accessible through the CDS may only be used under the terms of the licenses attributed to each particular resource.</dc:rights>
      <dct:accessRights xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">licence</dct:accessRights>
      <ows:BoundingBox xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows">
        <ows:LowerCorner>-30 25</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>45 72.5</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
    </csw:Record>
    