<csw:Record xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EO:ECMWF:DAT:SIS_BIODIVERSITY_ERA5_GLOBAL</dc:identifier>
      <dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Global bioclimatic indicators from 1979 to 2018 derived from reanalysis</dc:title>
      <dc:type xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">dataset</dc:type>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Habitats and biotopes</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sector: Biodiversity</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Product type: Reanalysis</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Product type: Climate indicies</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Spatial coverage: Global</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Variable domain: Land (biosphere)</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Temporal coverage: Past</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Provider: Copernicus C3S</dc:subject>
      <dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">netcdf</dc:format>
      <dct:abstract xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">This dataset provides a historical global reconstruction of bioclimatic indicators derived from ERA5 reanalysis on a latitude-longitude grid. These bioclimate indicators describe how the climate affects ecosystems, the services they deliver, and nature&#8217;s biodiversity. They are specifically relevant for applications within the biodiversity and ecosystem services community.
The 78 indicators cover bioclimatic variables from both land and marine environments characterising surface energy, drought, soil moisture and the (near-)surface climate including wind as well as Essential Climate Variables (ECV) relevant to the biodiversity community and are based on hourly or monthly ERA5 reanalysis data.
The bioclimatic indicators are widely used within the biodiversity community and have been chosen based on user requirements and consultation with stakeholders, in order to facilitate the direct use of climate information in screening analyses or in diverse downstream applications. The temporal resolution differs depending on the indicator varying between monthly, annual, and multi-annual averages.
This dataset was produced on behalf of the Copernicus Climate Change Service.

Variables in the dataset/application are:
Annual mean temperature (BIO01), Annual precipitation (BIO12), Aridity annual mean, Aridity coldest quarter, Aridity driest quarter, Aridity warmest quarter, Aridity wettest quarter, Cloud cover, Dry days, Evaporative fraction annual mean, Evaporative fraction coldest quarter, Evaporative fraction driest quarter, Evaporative fraction warmest quarter, Evaporative fraction wettest quarter, Frost days, Growing degree days, Growing degree days during growing season length, Growing season end of season, Growing season length, Growing season start of season, Isothermality (BIO03), Koeppen-Geiger class, Maximum 2m temperature, Maximum length of dry spells, Maximum precipitation, Maximum temperature of the warmest month (BIO05), Mean diurnal range (BIO02), Mean intensity of dry spells, Mean length of dry spells, Mean precipitation, Mean temperature of coldest quarter (BIO11), Mean temperature of driest quarter (BIO09), Mean temperature of warmest quarter (BIO10), Mean temperature of wettest quarter (BIO08), Meridional wind speed, Minimum 2m temperature, Minimum temperature of the coldest month (BIO06), Number of dry spells, Potential evaporation annual mean, Potential evaporation coldest quarter, Potential evaporation driest quarter, Potential evaporation warmest quarter, Potential evaporation wettest quarter, Precipitation of coldest quarter (BIO19), Precipitation of driest month (BIO14), Precipitation of driest quarter (BIO17), Precipitation of warmest quarter (BIO18), Precipitation of wettest month (BIO13), Precipitation of wettest quarter (BIO16), Precipitation seasonality (BIO15), Sea ice concentration, Sea surface temperature, Summer days, Surface latent heat flux annual mean, Surface latent heat flux coldest quarter, Surface latent heat flux driest quarter, Surface latent heat flux warmest quarter, Surface latent heat flux wettest quarter, Surface sensible heat flux annual mean, Surface sensible heat flux coldest quarter, Surface sensible heat flux driest quarter, Surface sensible heat flux warmest quarter, Surface sensible heat flux wettest quarter, Temperature annual range (BIO07), Temperature seasonality (BIO04), Volumetric soil water layer 1 annual mean, Volumetric soil water layer 1 coldest quarter, Volumetric soil water layer 1 driest quarter, Volumetric soil water layer 1 warmest quarter, Volumetric soil water layer 1 wettest quarter, Water vapour pressure, Wind speed, Zonal wind speed</dct:abstract>
      <dct:spatial xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">::EPSG:4326</dct:spatial>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/api/v2/terms/static/20191121_Copernicus_License_V1.2.pdf</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Content accessible through the CDS may only be used under the terms of the licenses attributed to each particular resource.</dc:rights>
      <dct:accessRights xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">licence</dct:accessRights>
      <ows:BoundingBox xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows">
        <ows:LowerCorner>-180 -90</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>180 90</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
    </csw:Record>
    