<csw:Record xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EO:ECMWF:DAT:CAMS_EUROPE_AIR_QUALITY_FORECASTS</dc:identifier>
      <dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">CAMS European air quality forecasts</dc:title>
      <dc:type xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">dataset</dc:type>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">airPollution</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Atmospheric conditions</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Variable domain: Atmosphere (composition)</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Parameter family: Aerosol</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Parameter family: Reactive gas</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Spatial coverage: Europe</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Product type: Forecast</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Product type: Analysis</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Temporal coverage: Future</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Temporal coverage: Past</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Temporal coverage: Present</dc:subject>
      <dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">None</dc:format>
      <dct:abstract xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">This dataset provides daily air quality analyses and forecasts for Europe. CAMS produces specific daily air quality analyses and forecasts for the European domain at significantly higher spatial resolution (0.1 degrees, approx. 10km) than is available from the global analyses and forecasts. The production is based on an ensemble of nine air quality forecasting systems across Europe. A median ensemble is calculated from individual outputs, since ensemble products yield on average better performance than the individual model products. The spread between the nine models are used to provide an estimate of the forecast uncertainty. The analysis combines model data with observations provided by the European Environment Agency (EEA) into a complete and consistent dataset using various data assimilation techniques depending upon the air-quality forecasting system used. In parallel, air quality forecasts are produced once a day for the next four days. Both the analysis and the forecast are available at hourly time steps at seven height levels. Note that only nitrogen monoxide, nitrogen dioxide, sulphur dioxide, ozone, PM2.5, PM10 and dust are regularly validated against in situ observations, and therefore forecasts of all other variables are unvalidated and should be considered experimental. Variables in the dataset/application are: Alder pollen, Ammonia, Birch pollen, Carbon monoxide, Dust, Grass pollen, Nitrogen dioxide, Nitrogen monoxide, Non-methane VOCs, Olive pollen, Ozone, Particulate matter d &lt; 10 &#65533;m (PM10), Particulate matter d &lt; 10 &#65533;m - wildfires only, Particulate matter d &lt; 2.5 &#65533;m (PM2.5), Particulate matter  
d &lt; 2.5 &#65533;m - anthropogenic fossil fuel carbon only, Particulate matter d &lt; 2.5 &#65533;m - anthropogenic wood burning carbon only, Peroxyacyl nitrates, Ragweed pollen, Secondary inorganic aerosol, Sulphur dioxx
ide</dct:abstract>
      <dct:spatial xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">::EPSG:4326</dct:spatial>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Content accessible through the ADS may only be used under the terms of the licenses attributed to each particular resource.</dc:rights>
      <dct:accessRights xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">licence</dct:accessRights>
      <ows:BoundingBox xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows">
        <ows:LowerCorner>-25 30</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>45 72</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
    </csw:Record>
    