<csw:Record xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EO:ECMWF:DAT:SATELLITE_UPPER_TROPOSPHERE_HUMIDITY</dc:identifier>
      <dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Upper tropospheric humidity gridded data from 1999 to present derived from satellite observations</dc:title>
      <dc:type xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">dataset</dc:type>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Meteorological geographical features</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Spatial coverage: Global</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Variable domain: Atmosphere (upper air)</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Temporal coverage: Past</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Temporal coverage: Present</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Product type: Satellite observations</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Provider: EUMETSAT SAF</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Provider: Copernicus C3S</dc:subject>
      <dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">netcdf</dc:format>
      <dct:abstract xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">Upper Tropospheric Humidity (UTH) is of key importance to the Earth&#8217;s greenhouse effect and understanding of climate change. It is considered an essential climate variable because it controls key atmospheric processes, including water vapour and cloud feedbacks that can amplify the climate system&#8217;s response to increases in other greenhouse gases.
The UTH Thematic Climate Data Record (TCDR) and Interim Climate Data Record (ICDR) are derived from observations from the AMSU-B and MHS microwave humidity sounder instruments on board the NOAA- and MetOp- satellite series. Instantaneous satellite observations are used to derive a spatio-temporal averaged data record. The data are available as twice daily (one for the ascending and the other for the descending passes) averages on a regular latitude/longitude grid. Additionally, the daily mean UTH is provided as a weighted average of ascending and descending orbits for all the grid points with valid ascending and descending observations.
UTH is the Jacobian weighted relative humidity in the upper troposphere. Its natural logarithm can be expressed as a linear function of the radiance emanated from water vapour emissions in the upper troposphere, expressed as brightness temperature. Various threshold masks are applied in order to identify and remove measurements contaminated by clouds, for example due to scattering by large ice particles in the presence of deep convection, and measurements contaminated by the surface. A viewing angle dependent analytical equation is used to convert off-nadir brightness temperatures into nadir equivalents, thereby providing a correction for limb darkening effects.
UTH is part of the Water Vapour ECV inventory in the CDS together with Total Column Water Vapour and Tropospheric Humidity Profiles.
The TCDR component of this dataset is brokered to the CDS and was originally produced on behalf of EUMETSAT Satellite Application Facility on Climate Monitoring (CMSAF) by the Met Office. The ICDR component has been delivered directly to the CDS and was originally produced on behalf of the C3S by the Met Office.

Variables in the dataset/application are:
Upper tropospheric humidty</dct:abstract>
      <dct:spatial xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">::EPSG:4326</dct:spatial>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/api/v2/terms/static/eumetsat-cm-saf-uth.pdf</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/api/v2/terms/static/licence-to-use-copernicus-products.pdf</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Content accessible through the CDS may only be used under the terms of the licenses attributed to each particular resource.</dc:rights>
      <dct:accessRights xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">licence</dct:accessRights>
      <ows:BoundingBox xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows">
        <ows:LowerCorner>-180 -90</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>180 90</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
    </csw:Record>
    