<csw:Record xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EO:ECMWF:DAT:INSITU_OBSERVATIONS_GNSS</dc:identifier>
      <dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">In-situ observations of water vapour and atmospheric delay from the ground-based GNSS network from 1996 to present</dc:title>
      <dc:type xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">dataset</dc:type>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Atmospheric conditions</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Product type: In-situ observations</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Spatial coverage: Global</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Variable domain: Atmosphere</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Variable domain: Atmosphere (upper air)</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Variable domain: Atmosphere (columnar property)</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Variable domain: Water Vapour (upper air)</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Temporal coverage: Past</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Temporal coverage: Present</dc:subject>
      <dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">CSV</dc:format>
      <dct:abstract xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">This dataset provides estimates of water vapour derived from atmospheric delays in Global Navigation Satellite System
(GNSS) radio signals.
The initial data is collected from two in situ ground-based network of GNSS receivers &#8211; the International GNSS Service
(IGS) and EUREF Permanent Network (EPN). The IGS collects, archives, and freely distributes GNSS data from a 
cooperatively operated global network of more than 500 ground-based GNSS stations since 1994. The EPN is a European 
network of more than 300 continuously operating GNSS reference stations with precisely known coordinates.
The fundamental observable of ground-based GNSS is the Zenith Total Delay (ZTD). This observable represents the 
propagation delay induced by the atmosphere on GNSS signals between the GNSS satellites and a GNSS receiver.
Using in-situ measurements of ZTD as well as ancillary meteorological data at the site, the vertically-integrated total 
amount if water vapour in the air column can be retrieved. This integrated quantity is referred to as Total Column 
Water Vapour (TCWV), or Total Precipitable Water (TPW), or Integrated Precipitable Water (IPW) or also Integrated Water
Vapour (IWV).
The TCWV values, with corresponding uncertainties, are based on the daily product of IGS and the 2nd reprocessing campaign
of the EPN (EPN-repro2). Both networks provide hourly records of ZTD as part of the products derived from GNSS data processing.
The GNSS TCWV derived from these ZTD data is a new product, made available exclusively for the Climate Data Store (CDS).
The data user must consider that while the EPN-repro2 consists of tropospheric parameters derived from consistently 
reprocessed data spanning multiple decades, the IGS daily product is a near real-time product which may contain jumps 
in the time-series when a new processing model is introduced. Therefore, IGS daily ZTD and TCWV should not be considered
as reference products. 
The method for retrieval of GNSS TCWV and details on the algorithms can be found in the documentation. For comparison, 
TCWV values from the ECMWF ERA5 reanalysis are also made available for the user.
The datasets can be downloaded as comma-separated values (CSV) files organized in two different ways:

One row per report: for each report all variables are provided as individual columns in one row (referenced as csv-lev in the variable lists below).
One row per observable: (no aggregation) each row provides information about one variable only (referenced as csv-obs in the variable lists below).


Variables in the dataset/application are:
Total column water vapour, Total column water vapour combined uncertainty, Total column water vapour era5, Zenith total delay, Zenith total delay random uncertainty

Variables in the dataset/application are:
City, Combined uncertainty, Era5, Height of station above sea level, Latitude, Longitude, Observation value, Observed variable, Organisation name, Random uncertainty, Report id, Report timestamp, Sensor altitude, Start date, Station name</dct:abstract>
      <dct:spatial xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">::EPSG:4326</dct:spatial>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/api/v2/terms/static/20180314_Copernicus_License_V1.1.pdf</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/api/v2/terms/static/gnss-data-policy.pdf</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Content accessible through the CDS may only be used under the terms of the licenses attributed to each particular resource.</dc:rights>
      <dct:accessRights xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">licence</dct:accessRights>
      <ows:BoundingBox xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows">
        <ows:LowerCorner>-180 -89</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>180 89</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
    </csw:Record>
    