<csw:Record xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EO:ECMWF:DAT:SIS_ENERGY_DERIVED_REANALYSIS</dc:identifier>
      <dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Climate and energy indicators for Europe from 1979 to present derived from reanalysis</dc:title>
      <dc:type xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">dataset</dc:type>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Atmospheric conditions, Energy resources, Utility and governmental services, Atmospheric Conditions and meteorological geographical features</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sector: Energy</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Variable domain: Atmosphere (dynamics)</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Product type: Reanalysis</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Spatial coverage: Europe</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Temporal coverage: Past</dc:subject>
      <dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">NetCDF and csv</dc:format>
      <dct:abstract xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">The Copernicus climate change service (C3S) operational energy dataset provides climate and energy indicators for the European energy sector. The climate-relevant indicators for the energy sector considered are: air temperature, precipitation, incoming solar radiation, wind speed at 10 m and 100 m, and mean sea level air pressure. The energy indicators are electricity demand and power generation from various sources: wind (both onshore and offshore), solar and hydro (run-of-river and reservoir) power. Depending on the indicator, the data are available at the national, regional and grid (approximately 30x30 km) level for most European countries. The spatial aggregation of data over land uses the Eurostat NUTS0 &amp; NUTS2 (Nomenclature des unit&#233;s territoriales statistiques, 2016) regions. The offshore variables (e.g. offshore wind power) use the European maritime region definitions MAR0 and MAR1. Further information on the NUTS and MAR regions can be found in the documentation.
The C3S Energy operational service is composed of three main streams: historical (1979-present), seasonal forecasts and projections (typically covering the period 1970-2100). This historical dataset (1979-present) produces reference climate variables based on the ERA5 reanalysis. Energy variables are generated by transforming the climate variables using a combination of statistical models and physically based data. A comprehensive set of measured energy supply and demand data has been collected from various sources such as the European Network of Transmission System Operators (ENTSO-E). These data provide a crucial reference to assess the robustness of the models used to convert climate into electric energy variables.
Similar datasets derived from seasonal forecasts and climate projections are also available in the Climate data store.
Data is provided for the European domain, in a multi-variable, multi-timescale view of the climate and energy systems. This is beneficial in anticipating important climate-driven changes in the energy sector, through either long-term planning or medium-term operational activities. This is also used to investigate the role of temperature on electricity demand across Europe, as well as its interaction with the variability of renewable energy generation.

Variables in the dataset/application are:
2m air temperature, Electricity demand, Hydro power generation reservoirs, Hydro power generation rivers, Pressure at sea level, Solar photovoltaic power generation, Surface downwelling shortwave radiation, Total precipitation, Wind power generation offshore, Wind power generation onshore, Wind speed</dct:abstract>
      <dct:spatial xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">::EPSG:4326</dct:spatial>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/api/v2/terms/static/licence-to-use-copernicus-products.pdf</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Content accessible through the CDS may only be used under the terms of the licenses attributed to each particular resource.</dc:rights>
      <dct:accessRights xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">licence</dct:accessRights>
      <ows:BoundingBox xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows">
        <ows:LowerCorner>-22 27</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>45 72</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
    </csw:Record>
    