<csw:Record xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EO:MO:DAT:WIND_GLO_WIND_L3_REP_OBSERVATIONS_012_005</dc:identifier>
      <dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Global Ocean Daily Gridded Reprocessed L3 Sea Surface Winds from Scatterometer</dc:title>
      <dc:type xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">series</dc:type>
      <dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">NetCDF-4</dc:format>
      <dct:abstract xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">'''Short description:''' 

For the Global Ocean - The product contains daily L3 gridded sea surface wind observations from available scatterometers with resolutions corresponding  to the L2 swath products:
*0.5 degrees grid for the 50 km scatterometer L2 inputs,
*0.25 degrees grid based on 25 km scatterometer swath observations,
*and 0.125 degrees based on 12.5 km scatterometer swath observations, i.e., from the coastal products. Data from ascending and descending passes are gridded separately. 

The reported wind is stress-equivalent wind with wind stress, wind stress curl and divergence. The REP L3 products follow the REP availability of the EUMETSAT OSI SAF L2 products and are available for: The ASCAT scatterometer on MetOp-A and Metop-B at 0.125 and 0.25 degrees; The Seawinds scatterometer on QuikSCAT at 0.25 and 0.5 degrees; The AMI scatterometer on ERS-1 and ERS-2 at 0.25 degrees; The OSCAT scatterometer on Oceansat-2 at 0.25 and 0.5 degrees;

'''DOI (product) :'''   
https://doi.org/10.48670/moi-00183</dct:abstract>
      <dct:spatial xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">EPSG::WGS 84 / Plate Carree (EPSG:32662)</dct:spatial>
      <dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">eng</dc:language>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">See Copernicus Marine Environment Monitoring Service Data commitments and licence at: http://marine.copernicus.eu/web/27-service-commitments-and-licence.php</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">license</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">No limitations on public access</dc:rights>
      <dct:accessRights xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">otherRestrictions</dct:accessRights>
      <dct:alternative xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">WIND_GLO_WIND_L3_REP_OBSERVATIONS_012_005</dct:alternative>
      <dct:created xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2012-08-26</dct:created>
      <ows:BoundingBox xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows">
        <ows:LowerCorner>-180 -90</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>180 90</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
    </csw:Record>
    