<csw:Record xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EO:EUM:DAT:0240</dc:identifier>
      <dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Poseidon-4 Altimetry Level 2 High Resolution (baseline version F06) - Sentinel-6 - Reprocessed</dc:title>
      <dc:type xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">series</dc:type>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ocean Surface Wind</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sea Surface Height</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wave</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">disableCustomizeCart</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Level 2 Data</dc:subject>
      <dct:modified xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2023-07-05</dct:modified>
      <dct:abstract xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">This is a reprocessed dataset at baseline F06, which is continued by the NRT/NTC data stream from 29/April/2022 onwards.

The level-2 high resolution products contain the typical altimetry measurements, like the altimeter range, the sea surface height, the wind speed, significant wave height and all required geophysical corrections and related flags derived either from RAW or RMC, or the combination of both. Two measurement data files are available (standard and reduced), each with a different number of variables. The standard data file includes 1 Hz and 20 Hz measurements for the Ku- band as well as geophysical corrections at 1 Hz and some at 20 Hz. The reduced data file contains only 1 Hz measurements for the Ku- and C-bands as well as geophysical corrections at 1 Hz.
Note that the HR data products only contain Ku-band measurements.

These products are suitable for users seeking information on sea state and those creating downstream added value products from multiple altimeters. Particularly for those seeking the highest resolution measurements.

Sentinel-6 is part of a series of Sentinel satellites, under the umbrella of the EU Copernicus programme. It is a collaborative Copernicus mission, implemented and co-funded by the European Commission, ESA, EUMETSAT and the USA, through NASA and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA).</dct:abstract>
      <dc:coverage xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Global</dc:coverage>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">-</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">copyright</dc:rights>
      <dct:accessRights xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">copyright</dct:accessRights>
      <dct:alternative xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">P4_2__HR_F06</dct:alternative>
      <dct:created xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2022-07-28</dct:created>
      <ows:BoundingBox xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows">
        <ows:LowerCorner>-180 -66.15</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>180 66.15</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
    </csw:Record>
    