<csw:Record xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EO:ECMWF:DAT:SATELLITE_AEROSOL_PROPERTIES</dc:identifier>
      <dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Aerosol properties gridded data from 1995 to present derived from satellite observations</dc:title>
      <dc:type xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">dataset</dc:type>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Atmospheric conditions</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Spatial coverage: Global</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Variable domain: Atmosphere (composition)</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Temporal coverage: Past</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Product type: Satellite observations</dc:subject>
      <dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">netcdf</dc:format>
      <dct:abstract xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">This data set provides observational records of aerosol properties obtained from observations collected by various satellite instruments. Aerosols are minor constituents of the atmosphere by mass, but critical components in terms of impact on climate. Aerosols influence the global radiation balance directly by scattering and absorbing radiation, and indirectly through influencing cloud reflectivity, cloud cover and cloud lifetime.
The main variables provided by this dataset are: aerosol optical depth, fine mode aerosol optical depth, dust aerosol optical depth, single scattering albedo, aerosol layer height and aerosol extinction coefficient. These variables are derived from observations from several sensors using a set of different processing techniques. This provides the possibility to derive a large set of complementary aerosol properties needed to describe the complex nature of atmospheric aerosols. Furthermore, different algorithms have their specific strengths and weaknesses, meaning that datasets originating from the same sensor but processed by different algorithms provide a way to evaluate uncertainties (e.g. areas of good or bad agreement between them). Altogether, the aerosol properties dataset is very extensive and offers a choice of complementary options &#8211; which is appropriate depends on the intended application.
Selected observational records in this dataset are extended in time on a semi-annual basis. At the moment of extending, these records are up-to-date until five months behind present time.   
This dataset is produced on behalf of C3S.

Variables in the dataset/application are:
Aerosol extinction coefficient, Aerosol layer height, Aerosol optical depth, Dust aerosol layer height, Dust aerosol optical depth, Fine mode aerosol optical depth, Single scattering albedo</dct:abstract>
      <dct:spatial xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">::EPSG:4326</dct:spatial>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/api/v2/terms/static/20180314_Copernicus_License_V1.1.pdf</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Content accessible through the CDS may only be used under the terms of the licenses attributed to each particular resource.</dc:rights>
      <dct:accessRights xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">licence</dct:accessRights>
      <ows:BoundingBox xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows">
        <ows:LowerCorner>-180 -90</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>180 90</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
    </csw:Record>
    