<csw:Record xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EO:ECMWF:DAT:REANALYSIS_CARRA_MODEL_LEVELS</dc:identifier>
      <dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Arctic regional reanalysis on model levels from 1991 to present</dc:title>
      <dc:type xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">dataset</dc:type>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Atmospheric conditions</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Product type: Reanalysis</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Spatial coverage: Arctic</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Variable domain: Atmosphere (upper air)</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Temporal coverage: Past</dc:subject>
      <dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">GRIB</dc:format>
      <dct:abstract xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">The C3S Arctic Regional Reanalysis (CARRA) dataset contains 3-hourly analyses and hourly short term forecasts of atmospheric and surface meteorological variables (temperature, humidity, wind, cloud, precipitation and turbulent kinetic energy) at 2.5 km resolution. Additionally, forecasts up to 30 hours initialised from the analyses at 00 and 12 UTC are available. 
The dataset includes two domains. The West domain covers Greenland, the Labrador Sea, Davis Strait, Baffin Bay, Denmark Strait, Iceland, Jan Mayen, the Greenland Sea, and parts of Svalbard. The East domain covers Svalbard, Franz Josef Land, Novaya Zemlya, Barents Sea, and the Northern parts of the Norwegian Sea and Scandinavia.
The dataset has been produced with the use of the HARMONIE-AROME state-of-the-art non-hydrostatic regional numerical weather prediction model. High resolution reanalysis for the Arctic region is particularly important because the climate change is more pronounced in the Arctic region than elsewhere in the Earth. This fact calls for a better description of this region providing additional details with respect to the global reanalyses (ERA5 for instance). The additional information is provided by the higher horizontal resolution, more local observations (from the Nordic countries and Greenland), better description of surface characteristics (high resolution satellite and physiographic data), high resolution non-hydrostatic dynamics and improved physical parameterisation of clouds and precipitation in particular.
The inputs to CARRA reanalysis are the observations, the ERA5 global reanalysis as lateral boundary conditions and the physiographic datasets describing the surface characteristics of the model. The observation values and information about their quality are used together to constrain the reanalysis where observations are available and provide information for the data assimilation system in areas in where less observations are available.
More details about the reanalysis dataset and the extensive input data are given in the Documentation section.

Variables in the dataset/application are:
Cloud cover, Graupel, Specific cloud ice water content, Specific cloud liquid water content, Specific cloud rain water content, Specific cloud snow water content, Specific humidity, Temperature, Turbulent kinetic energy, U-component of wind, V-component of wind</dct:abstract>
      <dct:spatial xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">::EPSG:4326</dct:spatial>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/api/v2/terms/static/licence-to-use-copernicus-products.pdf</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Content accessible through the CDS may only be used under the terms of the licenses attributed to each particular resource.</dc:rights>
      <dct:accessRights xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">licence</dct:accessRights>
      <ows:BoundingBox xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows">
        <ows:LowerCorner>180 65</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>-180 90</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
    </csw:Record>
    