<csw:Record xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EO:ECMWF:DAT:INSITU_OBSERVATIONS_IGRA_BASELINE_NETWORK</dc:identifier>
      <dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">In situ observations of meteorological variables from the Integrated Global Radiosounding Archive and the Radiosounding Harmonization dataset from 1978 onward</dc:title>
      <dc:type xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">dataset</dc:type>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Land cover</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Product type: In-situ observations</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Spatial coverage: Global</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Variable domain: Atmosphere (upper air)</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Temporal coverage: Past</dc:subject>
      <dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">csv</dc:format>
      <dct:abstract xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">This catalogue entry provides access to vertical profiles of standard meteorological variables. It includes two datasets. 
The first is version 2 of the Integrated Global Radiosounding Archive (IGRA) from 1978 which incorporates global 
radiosounding profiles of temperature, humidity and wind from a large number of data sources,
which is 30% larger than the previous version 1. IGRA v2 is the result of quality assurance procedures applied to the
radiosoundings data which can be grouped into eight categories: fundamental &#8220;sanity&#8221; checks, checks on the plausibility
and temporal consistency of surface elevation, internal consistency checks, checks for the repetition of values, 
checks for gross position errors in ship tracks, climatology-based checks, checks on the vertical and temporal 
consistency of temperature, and data completeness checks. No uncertainty estimation for the IGRA data is available.
The second is the Radiosounding HARMonization (RHARM) homogenized dataset which provides adjusted values of temperature,
relative humidity and wind, removing systematic effects (such as change in the measurement sensors,
solar radiation biases, sonde time-lag, calibration drifts, station relocation etc.) at 700 IGRA radiosounding stations
and radiosoundings from ships.
RHARM includes twice daily (0000 and 1200 UTC) radiosonde data at the mandatory levels (listed below).
At pressure levels lower than 10 hPa, temperature harmonized values are not provided because of the paucity of available 
observations and the issues affecting the measurements at those levels.
Relative humidity adjustments and data provision have been limited to 250 hPa owing to pervasive sensor 
performance issues at greater altitudes. 
Moreover, an estimation of the measurement uncertainty is provided for each value of the time series. 
The radiosounding significance levels are also adjusted per interpolation along with the corresponding uncertainties. 
The RHARM dataset thus inherits the IGRA quality assurance procedures, and additional quality checks are then applied,
performing tests on physical plausibility, accuracy of the bias adjustment, presence of outliers, and coherency check
for the adjustments applied at the significant levels. 
The IGRA dataset is provided by NOAA's National Centers for Environmental Information (NCEI) also through the IGRA data portal: 

IGRA data portal.

The RHARM dataset has been specifically developed for the Copernicus Climate Change Service (C3S).
Radiosoundings can be downloaded as comma-separated values (CSV) files organised in two different ways:

CSV one row per level: for each observed height all variables are provided as individual columns in one row. Each main variable has its dedicated columns for total uncertainty, where applies (referenced as csv-lev in the variable lists below).
CSV one row per observation: (no aggregation) each row provides information about one variable at one level only. All main variable are grouped together in the following columns: one for the observed variable (indicates variable in question), one for observation value and one column for total uncertainty (referenced as csv-obs in the variable lists below).


Variables in the dataset/application are:
Air dewpoint depression, Air temperature, Air temperature total uncertainty, Ascent speed, Eastward wind component, Eastward wind component total uncertainty, Frost point temperature, Geopotential height, Northward wind component, Northward wind component total uncertainty, Relative humidity, Relative humidity total uncertainty, Solar zenith angle, Water vapor volume mixing ratio, Wind from direction, Wind from direction total uncertainty, Wind speed, Wind speed total uncertainty

Variables in the dataset/application are:
Actual time, Air pressure, Height of station above sea level, Latitude, Longitude, Observation value, Observed variable, Radiosonde code, Report id, Report timestamp, Sensor model, Station name, Total uncertainty</dct:abstract>
      <dct:spatial xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">::EPSG:4326</dct:spatial>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/api/v2/terms/static/licence-to-use-copernicus-products.pdf</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/api/v2/terms/static/igra-data-policy.pdf</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Content accessible through the CDS may only be used under the terms of the licenses attributed to each particular resource.</dc:rights>
      <dct:accessRights xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">licence</dct:accessRights>
      <ows:BoundingBox xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows">
        <ows:LowerCorner>-180 -90</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>180 90</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
    </csw:Record>
    