<csw:Record xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EO:ECMWF:DAT:SATELLITE_SEA_LEVEL_BLACK_SEA</dc:identifier>
      <dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sea level daily gridded data from satellite observations for the Black Sea from 1993 to 2020</dc:title>
      <dc:type xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">dataset</dc:type>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Oceanographic geographical features</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Temporal coverage: Past</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Spatial coverage: Europe</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Product type: Satellite observations</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Variable domain: Ocean (physics)</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Provider: Copernicus C3S</dc:subject>
      <dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">NetCDF</dc:format>
      <dct:abstract xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">Sea level anomaly is the height of water over the mean sea surface in a given time and region. Up-to-date altimeter standards are used to estimate the sea level anomalies with a mapping algorithm dedicated to the Black sea region. Anomalies are computed with respect to a twenty-year mean reference period (1993-2012).
The steady number of reference satellite used in the production of this dataset contributes to the long-term stability of the sea level record. Improvements of the accuracy, sampling of meso-scale processes and of the high-latitude coverage were achieved by using a few additional satellite missions.
New data are provided with a delay of about 4-5 months relatively to near-real time or interim sea level products. This delay is mainly due to the timeliness of the input data, the centred processing temporal window and the validation process. However, this processing and validation adds stability and accuracy to the sea level variables and make them adapted to climate applications.
This dataset includes uncertainties for each grid cell. More details about the sea level retrieval, additional filters, optimisation procedures, and the error estimation are given in the Documentation section.

Variables in the dataset/application are:
Absolute dynamic topography, Absolute geostrophic velocity meridian component, Absolute geostrophic velocity zonal component, Geostrophic velocity anomalies meridian component, Geostrophic velocity anomalies zonal component, Sea level anomaly</dct:abstract>
      <dct:spatial xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">::EPSG:4326</dct:spatial>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/api/v2/terms/static/20180314_Copernicus_License_V1.1.pdf</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Content accessible through the CDS may only be used under the terms of the licenses attributed to each particular resource.</dc:rights>
      <dct:accessRights xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">licence</dct:accessRights>
      <ows:BoundingBox xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows">
        <ows:LowerCorner>-180 -90</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>180 90</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
    </csw:Record>
    