<csw:Record xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EO:ECMWF:DAT:SIS_WATER_LEVEL_CHANGE_TIMESERIES_CMIP6</dc:identifier>
      <dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Global sea level change time series from 1950 to 2050 derived from reanalysis and high resolution CMIP6 climate projections</dc:title>
      <dc:type xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">dataset</dc:type>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sea regions</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Spatial coverage: Global</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Variable domain: Ocean (physics)</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Temporal coverage: Past</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Temporal coverage: Future</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Product type: Reanalysis</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Product type: Climate projections</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Provider: Copernicus C3S</dc:subject>
      <dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">netcdf</dc:format>
      <dct:abstract xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">This dataset provides time series of global sea level related variables including tides, storm surges and sea level rise from 1950 to 2050 based on hydrodynamic modelling. The dataset provides a basis for studies, for instance, aiming to evaluate sea level variability, coastal flooding, coastal erosion, and accessibility of ports.
The time series are computed using the Deltares Global Tide and Surge Model (GTSM) version 3.0, a hydrodynamic model that dynamically simulates water levels at 10-minute intervals and capable of using input forcing from reanalysis and climate models. The dataset is based on climate forcing from ERA5 global reanalysis and 5 Global Climate Models (GCMs) of the high resolution Coupled Model Intercomparison Project Phase 6 (CMIP6) global climate projection dataset from the High Resolution Model Intercomparison Project (HighResMIP) multi-model ensemble. By making use of the HighResMIP multi-model ensemble, it is possible to quantify the uncertainties associated with the input climate forcing in this dataset.
The simulations for the historical period may be selected from either ERA5 reanalysis or historical simulations from the GCMs. The future period simulations are from the GCMs and are based on global climate projections using the high-emissions scenario SSP5-8.5 (Shared Socioeconomic Pathways). An exception to this is the tidal elevation variable that is not based on any future climate scenarios, since the tide-generating forces considered in GTSM are not related to any climatological nor meteorological conditions.
This dataset was produced on behalf of the Copernicus Climate Change Service.

Variables in the dataset/application are:
Mean sea level, Storm surge residual, Tidal elevation, Total water level</dct:abstract>
      <dct:spatial xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">::EPSG:4326</dct:spatial>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/api/v2/terms/static/licence-to-use-copernicus-products.pdf</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Content accessible through the CDS may only be used under the terms of the licenses attributed to each particular resource.</dc:rights>
      <dct:accessRights xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">licence</dct:accessRights>
      <ows:BoundingBox xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows">
        <ows:LowerCorner>-180 -90</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>180 90</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
    </csw:Record>
    