<csw:Record xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EO:ECMWF:DAT:CEMS_FIRE_HISTORICAL</dc:identifier>
      <dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fire danger indices historical data from the Copernicus Emergency Management Service</dc:title>
      <dc:type xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">dataset</dc:type>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Land cover</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Product type: Reanalysis</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Spatial coverage: Global</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Variable domain: Land (biosphere)</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Temporal coverage: Past</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Provider: Copernicus CEMS</dc:subject>
      <dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">netcdf</dc:format>
      <dct:abstract xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">This data set provides complete historical reconstruction of meteorological conditions favourable to the start, spread and sustainability of fires. The fire danger metrics  provided are part of a vast dataset produced by the Copernicus Emergency Management Service for the
European Forest Fire Information System (EFFIS). The European Forest Fire Information System incorporates the fire danger indices for three different models developed in Canada, United States and Australia. In this dataset the fire danger indices are calculated using weather forecast from historical simulations provided by ECMWF ERA5 reanalysis.
ERA5 by combining  model data and  a vast set of quality controlled observations provides a  globally complete and consistent data-set and is regarded as a good proxy for observed atmospheric conditions.
The selected data records in this data set are regularly extended with time as ERA5 forcing data become available. 
This dataset is produced by ECMWF in its role of the computational centre for fire danger forecast of the CEMS,  on behalf of the Joint Research Centre which is the managing entity of the service.

Variables in the dataset/application are:
Build-up index, Burning index, Danger rating, Drought code, Duff moisture code, Energy release component, Fine fuel moisture code, Fire daily severity index, Fire danger index, Fire weather index, Ignition component, Initial spread index, Keetch-Byram drought index, Spread component</dct:abstract>
      <dct:spatial xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">::EPSG:4326</dct:spatial>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/api/v2/terms/static/20180314_Copernicus_License_V1.1.pdf</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Content accessible through the CDS may only be used under the terms of the licenses attributed to each particular resource.</dc:rights>
      <dct:accessRights xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">licence</dct:accessRights>
      <ows:BoundingBox xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows">
        <ows:LowerCorner>-180 -90</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>180 90</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
    </csw:Record>
    