<csw:Record xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EO:MO:DAT:INSITU_GLO_PHY_UV_DISCRETE_NRT_013_048</dc:identifier>
      <dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Global Ocean- in-situ Near real time observations of ocean currents</dc:title>
      <dc:type xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">series</dc:type>
      <dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">NetCDF-4</dc:format>
      <dct:abstract xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">'''Short description'''
This product is entirely dedicated to ocean current data observed in near-real time. Current data from 3 different types of instruments are distributed:
* The near-surface zonal and meridional velocities calculated along the trajectories of the drifting buoys which are part of the DBCP&#8217;s Global Drifter Program. These data are delivered together with wind stress components and surface temperature. 
* The near-surface zonal and meridional total velocities, and near-surface radial velocities, measured by High Frequency radars that are part of the European High Frequency radar Network. These data are delivered together with standard deviation of near-surface zonal and meridional raw velocities, Geometrical Dilution of Precision (GDOP), quality flags and metadata.
* The zonal and meridional velocities, at parking depth and in surface, calculated along the trajectories of the floats which are part of the Argo Program.

'''DOI (product) :'''
https://doi.org/10.48670/moi-00041</dct:abstract>
      <dct:spatial xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">EPSG::WGS84 / Simple Mercator (EPSG:41001)</dct:spatial>
      <dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">eng</dc:language>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">See Copernicus Marine Environment Monitoring Service Data commitments and licence at: http://marine.copernicus.eu/web/27-service-commitments-and-licence.php</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">license</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">No limitations on public access</dc:rights>
      <dct:accessRights xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">otherRestrictions</dct:accessRights>
      <dct:alternative xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">INSITU_GLO_PHY_UV_DISCRETE_NRT_013_048</dct:alternative>
      <dct:created xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2012-08-26</dct:created>
      <ows:BoundingBox xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows">
        <ows:LowerCorner>-180 -90</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>180 90</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
    </csw:Record>
    