<csw:Record xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EO:MO:DAT:GLOBAL_REANALYSIS_PHY_001_026</dc:identifier>
      <dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Global Ocean Ensemble Physics Reanalysis - Low resolution</dc:title>
      <dc:type xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">series</dc:type>
      <dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">NetCDF-4</dc:format>
      <dct:abstract xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">'''Short description:'''
You can find here the new Mercator Ocean (Toulouse, FR) Global Ocean Ensemble Reanalysis: monthly means of Temperature, Salinity, Currents and Ice variables at 1 degree horizontal resolution for  75 vertical levels, starting from 1993 onward.
 
Global ocean reanalyses are homogeneous 3D gridded descriptions of the physical state of the ocean spanning several decades, produced with a numerical ocean model constrained with data assimilation of satellite and in situ observations. The multi-model ensemble approach allows uncertainties or error bars in the ocean state to be estimated. The ensemble mean may even provide, for certain regions and/or periods, a more reliable estimate than any individual reanalysis product.

The four reanalyses, used to create the ensemble, covering &#8220;altimetric era&#8221; period (starting from 1st of January 1993) during which altimeter altimetry data observations are available:
* GLORYS2V4 from Mercator Ocean (Fr) ;
* ORAS5 from ECMWF ;
* GloSea5 from Met Office (UK) ;
* and C-GLORS05 from CMCC (It). ;
provided as four different time series of global ocean simulations 3D monthly estimates, post-processed to create this Global Reanalysis Ensemble Product (GREP). Available variables are temperature, salinity, velocities and ice variables.

These reanalyses are built to be as close as possible to the observations (i.e. realistic) and in agreement with the model physics. The numerical products available for users are monthly mean averages describing the ocean from surface to bottom (5900 m).

'''DOI (product) :'''   
https://doi.org/10.48670/moi-00023</dct:abstract>
      <dct:spatial xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">EPSG::WGS 84 (EPSG:4326)</dct:spatial>
      <dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">eng</dc:language>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">See Copernicus Marine Environment Monitoring Service Data commitments and licence at: http://marine.copernicus.eu/web/27-service-commitments-and-licence.php</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">license</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">No limitations on public access</dc:rights>
      <dct:accessRights xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">otherRestrictions</dct:accessRights>
      <dct:alternative xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">GLOBAL_REANALYSIS_PHY_001_026</dct:alternative>
      <dct:created xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2012-08-26</dct:created>
      <ows:BoundingBox xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows">
        <ows:LowerCorner>-180 -90</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>180 90</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
    </csw:Record>
    