<csw:Record xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EO:MO:DAT:SST_MED_SST_L4_NRT_OBSERVATIONS_010_004</dc:identifier>
      <dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mediterranean Sea High Resolution and Ultra High Resolution Sea Surface Temperature Analysis</dc:title>
      <dc:type xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">series</dc:type>
      <dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">NetCDF-3</dc:format>
      <dct:abstract xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">'''Short description:''' 
For the Mediterranean Sea (MED), the CNR MED Sea Surface Temperature (SST) processing chain provides daily gap-free (L4) maps at high (HR 0.0625&#176;) and ultra-high (UHR 0.01&#176;) spatial resolution over the Mediterranean Sea. Remotely-sensed L4 SST datasets are operationally produced and distributed in near-real time by the Consiglio Nazionale delle Ricerche - Gruppo di Oceanografia da Satellite (CNR-GOS). These SST products are based on the nighttime images collected by the infrared sensors mounted on different satellite platforms, and cover the Southern European Seas. The CNR-GOS processing chain includes several modules, from the data extraction and preliminary quality control, to cloudy pixel removal and satellite images collating/merging. A two-step algorithm finally allows to interpolate SST data at high (HR 0.0625&#176;) and ultra-high (UHR 0.01&#176;) spatial resolution, applying statistical techniques. These L4 data are also used to estimate the SST anomaly with respect to a pentad climatology. The basic design and the main algorithms used are described in the following papers.

'''DOI (product) :'''   
https://doi.org/10.48670/moi-00172</dct:abstract>
      <dct:spatial xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">EPSG::WGS 84 (EPSG 4326)</dct:spatial>
      <dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">eng</dc:language>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">See Copernicus Marine Environment Monitoring Service Data commitments and licence at: http://marine.copernicus.eu/web/27-service-commitments-and-licence.php</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">license</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">No limitations on public access</dc:rights>
      <dct:accessRights xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">otherRestrictions</dct:accessRights>
      <dct:alternative xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">SST_MED_SST_L4_NRT_OBSERVATIONS_010_004</dct:alternative>
      <dct:created xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2009-09-30</dct:created>
      <ows:BoundingBox xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows">
        <ows:LowerCorner>-180 -90</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>180 90</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
    </csw:Record>
    