<csw:Record xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EO:MO:DAT:SST_GLO_SST_L4_NRT_OBSERVATIONS_010_001</dc:identifier>
      <dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Global Ocean OSTIA Sea Surface Temperature and Sea Ice Analysis</dc:title>
      <dc:type xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">series</dc:type>
      <dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">NetCDF-3</dc:format>
      <dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">NetCDF-4</dc:format>
      <dct:abstract xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">'''Short description:''' 

For the Global Ocean- the OSTIA global foundation Sea Surface Temperature product provides daily gap-free maps of : Foundation Sea Surface Temperature at 0.05&#176; x 0.05&#176; horizontal grid resolution, using in-situ and satellite data from both infrared and microwave radiometers; Sea Surface Temperature anomaly from the Pathfinder climatology at 0.25&#176; x 0.25&#176; horizontal resolution; Estimates of SST bias in data from satellites contributing to the OSTIA SST analysis at 0.25&#176; x 0.25&#176; horizontal resolution. 

The Operational Sea Surface Temperature and Ice Analysis (OSTIA) system is run by the UK's Met Office. OSTIA uses satellite data provided by the GHRSST project together with in-situ observations to determine the sea surface temperature.
A high resolution (1/20&#176; - approx. 6 km) daily analysis of sea surface temperature (SST) is produced for the global ocean and some lakes. SST anomalies are calculated at 1/4&#176; resolution from the daily Pathfinder climatology. As part of the analysis procedure, an estimate of the bias in the contributing satellite sensors is made. This is done by calculating match-ups between each satellite sensor and a reference data-set (currently comprised of drifting and moored buoy in situ data and nighttime VIIRS and dual-view SLSTR satellite SSTs). These differences are then analysed to produce gridded fields of bias for each sensor.

'''DOI (product) :'''   
https://doi.org/10.48670/moi-00165</dct:abstract>
      <dct:spatial xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">EPSG::WGS 84 (EPSG:4326)</dct:spatial>
      <dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">eng</dc:language>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">See Copernicus Marine Environment Monitoring Service Data commitments and licence at: http://marine.copernicus.eu/web/27-service-commitments-and-licence.php</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">license</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">No limitations on public access</dc:rights>
      <dct:accessRights xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">otherRestrictions</dct:accessRights>
      <dct:alternative xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">SST_GLO_SST_L4_NRT_OBSERVATIONS_010_001</dct:alternative>
      <dct:created xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2009-09-30</dct:created>
      <ows:BoundingBox xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows">
        <ows:LowerCorner>-180 -90</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>180 90</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
    </csw:Record>
    