<csw:Record xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EO:MO:DAT:WAVE_GLO_PHY_SPC_L4_NRT_014_004</dc:identifier>
      <dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">GLOBAL OCEAN L4 SPECTRAL PARAMETERS FROM NRT SATELLITE MEASUREMENTS</dc:title>
      <dc:type xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">series</dc:type>
      <dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">NetCDF-4</dc:format>
      <dct:abstract xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">'''Short description:'''

Near-Real-Time multi-mission global satellite-based spectral integral parameters. Only valid data are used, based on the L3 corresponding product. Included wave parameters are partition significant wave height, partition peak period and partition peak or principal direction. Those parameters are propagated in space and time at a 3-hour timestep and on a regular space grid, providing information of the swell propagation characteristics, from source to land. One file gathers one swell system, gathering observations originating from the same storm source. This product is processed by the WAVE-TAC multi-mission SAR data processing system to serve in near-real time the main operational oceanography and climate forecasting centers in Europe and worldwide. It processes data from the following SAR missions: Sentinel-1A and Sentinel-1B. All the spectral parameter measurements are optimally interpolated using swell observations belonging to the same swell field. The SAR data processing system produces wave integral parameters by partition (partition significant wave height, partition peak period and partition peak or principal direction) and the associated standard deviation and density of propagated observations. 

'''DOI (product) :'''   
https://doi.org/10.48670/moi-00175</dct:abstract>
      <dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">eng</dc:language>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">See Copernicus Marine Environment Monitoring Service Data commitments and licence at: http://marine.copernicus.eu/web/27-service-commitments-and-licence.php</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">license</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">No limitations on public access</dc:rights>
      <dct:accessRights xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">otherRestrictions</dct:accessRights>
      <dct:alternative xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">WAVE_GLO_PHY_SPC_L4_NRT_014_004</dct:alternative>
      <dct:created xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2012-08-26</dct:created>
      <ows:BoundingBox xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows">
        <ows:LowerCorner>-180 -90</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>180 90</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
    </csw:Record>
    