<csw:Record xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:geonet="http://www.fao.org/geonetwork" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows" xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier>e61d0641-ef07-4224-a6ed-6d2d42a4ef23</dc:identifier>
      <dc:date>2021-05-12T17:28:50.852Z</dc:date>
      <dc:title>Riparian Zones Delineation (raster), Aug. 2015</dc:title>
      <dc:type>dataset</dc:type>
      <dc:subject>Land cover</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>EEA39</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>freshwater ecosystem</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>bank (land)</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>riparian zone</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>land use</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>filtration</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>landscape alteration</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>European</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>2017 3.6.2</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>Biodiversity</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>Water</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>Land use</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>environment</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>imageryBaseMapsEarthCover</dc:subject>
      <dc:format>GeoTIFF</dc:format>
      <dct:abstract>Riparian zones represent transitional areas occurring between land and freshwater ecosystems, characterised by distinctive hydrology, soil and biotic conditions and strongly influenced by the stream water. They provide a wide range of riparian functions (e.g. chemical filtration, flood control, bank stabilization, aquatic life and riparian wildlife support, etc.) and ecosystem services.

The Riparian Zones products support the objectives of several European legal acts and policy initiatives, such as the EU Biodiversity Strategy to 2020, the Habitats and Birds Directives and the Water Framework Directive.

The delineation of Riparian Zones is based on a complex spatial modelling approach, making use of the Riparian Zones&#8217; LC/LU classification, large-scale earth observation data and a range of additional geo-data sources, as well as derived spatially explicit indicators. Inputs are regionally parameterised and weighted according to relative importance in a fuzzy modelling approach. The zones provide a majority of riparian functions with a focus on ecosystem services.

The production of the Riparian Zones products was coordinated by the European Environment Agency in the frame of the EU Copernicus programme.</dct:abstract>
      <dc:description>Riparian zones represent transitional areas occurring between land and freshwater ecosystems, characterised by distinctive hydrology, soil and biotic conditions and strongly influenced by the stream water. They provide a wide range of riparian functions (e.g. chemical filtration, flood control, bank stabilization, aquatic life and riparian wildlife support, etc.) and ecosystem services.

The Riparian Zones products support the objectives of several European legal acts and policy initiatives, such as the EU Biodiversity Strategy to 2020, the Habitats and Birds Directives and the Water Framework Directive.

The delineation of Riparian Zones is based on a complex spatial modelling approach, making use of the Riparian Zones&#8217; LC/LU classification, large-scale earth observation data and a range of additional geo-data sources, as well as derived spatially explicit indicators. Inputs are regionally parameterised and weighted according to relative importance in a fuzzy modelling approach. The zones provide a majority of riparian functions with a focus on ecosystem services.

The production of the Riparian Zones products was coordinated by the European Environment Agency in the frame of the EU Copernicus programme.</dc:description>
      <dc:rights>otherRestrictions</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights>otherRestrictions</dc:rights>
      <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
      <dc:source>The calculation is based on the stratification of different hydrological and geomorphological parameters. These parameters are derived from the input datasets and are weighted differently dependent on their significance and quality. The resulting membership degree of each input parameter is finally combined into a single membership degree expressing the likelihood of an area to be part of a potential riparian zone. Qualitative assessment: due to the absence of European-wide harmonized reference data on the location and characteristics of riparian zones in sufficient thematic detail, a qualitative expert assessment approach has been chosen for the riparian zones layer, making use of the unique expertise of the freelance expert consultants who are available to the project team and who are recognized among the most renowned European experts in this domain, being also the authors of the most relevant scientific publications in the recent years. The experts conducted an in-depth review of the riparian zones delineation modelling approach and the associated relevant algorithms and membership functions, which were checked and approved by them. The experts provided also support and advise on the correct model parameterization and final modelling of the riparian zones products, such that the final results are considered properly quality-assessed and validated by this scientific expert-assessment approach.</dc:source>
      <dc:format>GeoTIFF</dc:format>
      <ows:BoundingBox crs="urn:ogc:def:crs:EPSG:6.6:4326">
        <ows:LowerCorner>27.6375 -31.2684</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>66.5662 -13.4198</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
      <ows:BoundingBox crs="urn:ogc:def:crs:EPSG:6.6:4326">
        <ows:LowerCorner>34.5619 -10.6198</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>71.1855 44.8212</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
      <dc:URI protocol="WWW:LINK-1.0-http--link">https://land.copernicus.eu/local/riparian-zones/riparian-zones-delineation/view</dc:URI>
      <dc:URI protocol="OGC:WMS" description="DEL">https://image.discomap.eea.europa.eu/arcgis/services/RiparianZones/DEL/MapServer/WMSServer?request=GetCapabilities&amp;service=WMS</dc:URI>
      <dc:URI protocol="ESRI:REST">https://image.discomap.eea.europa.eu/arcgis/rest/services/RiparianZones/DEL/MapServer</dc:URI>
      <dc:URI protocol="OGC:WMS" name="Downloads" description="Downloads">https://image.discomap.eea.europa.eu/arcgis/services/RiparianZones/DEL/MapServer/WMSServer?request=GetCapabilities&amp;service=WMS</dc:URI>
      <dc:URI protocol="image/png">https://sdi.eea.europa.eu/public/catalogue-graphic-overview/2738bb1f-6b50-47e9-aba9-50157cb7228f.png</dc:URI>
    </csw:Record>
    