<rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:skos="http://www.w3.org/2004/02/skos/core#" xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xslUtils="java:org.fao.geonet.util.XslUtil" xmlns:dcat="http://www.w3.org/ns/dcat#" xmlns:gmd="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/gmd" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/" xmlns:void="http://www.w3.org/TR/void/" xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dcat:CatalogRecord rdf:about="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu:443//geonetwork/metadata/eu.copernicus.climate.satellite-carbon-dioxide">
        <foaf:primaryTopic rdf:resource="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu:443//geonetwork/resource/10.24381/cds.f74805c8"/>
        <dct:issued>2018-03-28</dct:issued>
        <dct:modified>2018-03-28</dct:modified>
        <dct:references>
          <rdf:Description rdf:about="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu:443//geonetwork/srv/eng/xml.metadata.get?uuid=eu.copernicus.climate.satellite-carbon-dioxide">
            <dct:format>
              <dct:IMT>
                <rdf:value>application/xml</rdf:value>
                <rdfs:label>XML</rdfs:label>
              </dct:IMT>
            </dct:format>
          </rdf:Description>
        </dct:references>
        <dct:references>
          <rdf:Description rdf:about="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu:443//geonetwork?uuid=eu.copernicus.climate.satellite-carbon-dioxide">
            <dct:format>
              <dct:IMT>
                <rdf:value>text/html</rdf:value>
                <rdfs:label>HTML</rdfs:label>
              </dct:IMT>
            </dct:format>
          </rdf:Description>
        </dct:references>
      </dcat:CatalogRecord>
      <dcat:Dataset rdf:about="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu:443//geonetwork/resource/10.24381/cds.f74805c8">
        <dct:identifier>10.24381/cds.f74805c8</dct:identifier>
        <dct:title>Carbon dioxide data from 2002 to present derived from satellite observations</dct:title>
        <dct:abstract>This dataset provides observations of atmospheric carbon dioxide (CO2) amounts obtained from observations collected by several current and historical satellite instruments. 
Carbon dioxide is a naturally occurring Greenhouse Gas (GHG), but one whose abundance has been increased substantially above its pre-industrial value of some 280 ppm by human activities, primarily because of emissions from combustion of fossil fuels, deforestation and other land-use change. 
The annual cycle (especially in the northern hemisphere) is primarily due to seasonal uptake and release of atmospheric CO2 by terrestrial vegetation.
Atmospheric carbon dioxide abundance is indirectly observed by various satellite instruments.
These instruments measure spectrally resolved near-infrared and/or infrared radiation reflected or emitted by the Earth and its atmosphere. 
In the measured signal, molecular absorption signatures from carbon dioxide and other constituent gasses can be identified. 
It is through analysis of those absorption lines in these radiance observations that the averaged carbon dioxide abundance in the sampled atmospheric column can be determined.
The software used to analyse the absorption lines and determine the carbon dioxide concentration in the sampled atmospheric column is referred to as the retrieval algorithm. 
For this dataset, carbon dioxide abundances have been determined by applying several algorithms to different satellite instruments. 
Typically, different algorithms have different strengths and weaknesses and therefore, which product to use for a given application typically depends on the application.
The data set consists of 2 types of products: 

column-averaged mixing ratios of CO2, denoted XCO2
mid-tropospheric CO2 columns.  

The XCO2 products have been retrieved from SCIAMACHY/ENVISAT, TANSO-FTS/GOSAT, TANSO-FTS2/GOSAT2 and OCO-2.
The mid-tropospheric CO2 product has been retrieved from the IASI instruments on-board the Metop satellite series and from AIRS. 
The XCO2 products are available as Level 2 (L2) products (satellite orbit tracks) and as Level 3 (L3) product (gridded). 
The L2 products are available as individual sensor products (SCIAMACHY: BESD and WFMD algorithms; GOSAT: OCFP and SRFP algorithms) and as a multi-sensor merged product (EMMA algorithm). 
The L3 XCO2 product is provided in OBS4MIPS format. 
The IASI and AIRS products are available as L2 products generated with the NLIS algorithm.
This data set is updated on a yearly basis, with each update cycle adding (if required) a new data version for the entire period, up to one year behind real time.
This dataset is produced on behalf of C3S with the exception of the SCIAMACHY and AIRS L2 products that were generated in the framework of the GHG-CCI project of the European Space Agency (ESA) Climate Change Initiative (CCI).

Variables in the dataset/application are:
Column-average dry-air mole fraction of atmospheric carbon dioxide (XCO2), Mid-tropospheric columns of atmospheric carbon dioxide (CO2)</dct:abstract>
        <dcat:theme rdf:resource="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu:443//geonetwork/thesaurus/GEMET%20-%20INSPIRE%20themes%2C%20version%201.0/Atmospheric conditions"/>
        <dcat:theme rdf:resource="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu:443//geonetwork/thesaurus/Climate%20Data%20Store%20facets/Variable domain: Atmosphere (composition)"/>
        <dcat:theme rdf:resource="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu:443//geonetwork/thesaurus/Climate%20Data%20Store%20facets/Product type: Satellite observations"/>
        <dcat:theme rdf:resource="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu:443//geonetwork/thesaurus/Climate%20Data%20Store%20facets/Temporal coverage: Past"/>
        <dcat:theme rdf:resource="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu:443//geonetwork/thesaurus/Climate%20Data%20Store%20facets/Spatial coverage: Global"/>
        <dcat:theme rdf:resource="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu:443//geonetwork/thesaurus/iso/topicCategory/climatologyMeteorologyAtmosphere"/>
        <foaf:thumbnail rdf:resource="https://datastore.copernicus-climate.eu/c3s/published-forms-v2/c3sprod/satellite-carbon-dioxide/overview.png"/>
        <dct:spatial>
          <ogc:Polygon xmlns:ogc="http://www.opengis.net/rdf#">
            <ogc:asWKT rdf:datatype="http://www.opengis.net/rdf#WKTLiteral">&lt;http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/OGC/1.3/CRS84&gt;
            Polygon((0 -70, 0 70, 360 70, 360 -70, 0 -70))</ogc:asWKT>
          </ogc:Polygon>
        </dct:spatial>
        <dct:temporal>2002-10-01
          /
          2016-12-31</dct:temporal>
        <dct:publisher rdf:resource="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu:443//geonetwork/organization/ECMWF"/>
        <dct:accrualPeriodicity>asNeeded</dct:accrualPeriodicity>
        <dct:language>eng</dct:language>
        <dct:license>licence</dct:license>
        <dct:license>https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/api/v2/terms/static/ghg-cci.pdf</dct:license>
        <dcat:distribution rdf:resource="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/cdsapp#!/dataset/10.24381/cds.f74805c8"/>
        <dcat:distribution rdf:resource="#"/>
        <dcat:distribution rdf:resource="#"/>
        <dcat:distribution rdf:resource="#"/>
        <dcat:distribution rdf:resource="#"/>
        <dcat:distribution rdf:resource="#"/>
        <dcat:distribution rdf:resource="#"/>
        <dcat:dataQuality>EC Copernicus program</dcat:dataQuality>
      </dcat:Dataset>
    </rdf:RDF>
    