<rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:skos="http://www.w3.org/2004/02/skos/core#" xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xslUtils="java:org.fao.geonet.util.XslUtil" xmlns:dcat="http://www.w3.org/ns/dcat#" xmlns:gmd="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/gmd" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/" xmlns:void="http://www.w3.org/TR/void/" xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dcat:CatalogRecord rdf:about="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu:443//geonetwork/metadata/eu.copernicus.climate.provider-cems-without">
        <foaf:primaryTopic rdf:resource="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu:443//geonetwork/resource/eu.copernicus.climate.provider-cems-without"/>
        <dct:issued>2018-03-28</dct:issued>
        <dct:modified>2018-03-28</dct:modified>
        <dct:references>
          <rdf:Description rdf:about="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu:443//geonetwork/srv/eng/xml.metadata.get?uuid=eu.copernicus.climate.provider-cems-without">
            <dct:format>
              <dct:IMT>
                <rdf:value>application/xml</rdf:value>
                <rdfs:label>XML</rdfs:label>
              </dct:IMT>
            </dct:format>
          </rdf:Description>
        </dct:references>
        <dct:references>
          <rdf:Description rdf:about="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu:443//geonetwork?uuid=eu.copernicus.climate.provider-cems-without">
            <dct:format>
              <dct:IMT>
                <rdf:value>text/html</rdf:value>
                <rdfs:label>HTML</rdfs:label>
              </dct:IMT>
            </dct:format>
          </rdf:Description>
        </dct:references>
      </dcat:CatalogRecord>
      <dcat:Dataset rdf:about="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu:443//geonetwork/resource/eu.copernicus.climate.provider-cems-without">
        <dct:identifier>eu.copernicus.climate.provider-cems-without</dct:identifier>
        <dct:title>Copernicus Emergency Management Service contributions to the Climate Data Store</dct:title>
        <dct:abstract>This page provides a brief overview of the Copernicus Emergency Management Service (CEMS) datasets made available to users 
through the Climate Data Store (CDS). The CEMS is one of six thematic information services provided by the 
European Union's Copernicus Earth Observation Programme, known as "Europe's eyes on Earth". 
Created using satellite, in-situ, and model data, CEMS products provide support to all actors involved in the management of natural and 
man-made disasters throughout the disaster lifecycle. This therefore includes prevention, preparedness, response and recovery activities.
CEMS consists of two components:


On-demand Mapping, of global coverage that provides satellite-based maps on the extent and impact of disasters for specific 
events requested by eligible users


Early Warning and Monitoring, of European and global coverage that provides overviews of near real-time and early warning 
information for ongoing and forecasted events


ECMWF contributes to two of the three early warning prediction systems that comprise the Early Warning and Monitoring component, these are Floods (CEMS-Floods) and Fires 
(CEMS-Fires). A third prediction system for Droughts is produced elsewhere. For Floods, there are the Global and European Flood Awareness Systems (GloFAS and EFAS). 
For Fires, there is the European Forest Fire Information Service (EFFIS) and the Global Wildfire Information Service (GWIS - under development). These services 
are delivered through dedicated Information Services. More information about CEMS Floods and CEMS Fires Early Warning Systems (EWS) data and services delivered by 
ECMWF can be found on the dedicated wiki pages.
CEMS-Floods
There are three types of hydrological datasets at the native EFAS and GloFAS temporal and spatial resolutions:


Historical (or reanalysis) multi-decadal simulations, that aim to reproduce observations and serve as a reference dataset. They are used for initial conditions, to define climatology and thresholds for forecast evaluation.


Real-time forecasts, that aim to represent possible scenarios of the future. Both seasonal and shorter range forecasts are produced.


Reforecasts, that are a set of forecasts for the past produced with a model configuration that is as close as possible to the operational system. They are used to define thresholds and for forecast evaluation. Both seasonal and shorter range reforecasts are produced.


All datasets are updated after a major operational system upgrade and are given a new version number.
CEMS-Fire
There are two types of fire danger datasets that for ease of use are provided at the same spatial resolution of the leading datasets (e.g. ERA5, System-5).


Historical (or reanalysis) multi-decadal simulations, that aim to reproduce observations and serve as a reference dataset. They are used for initial conditions, to define climatology and thresholds for forecast evaluation.


Reforecasts, that are a set of forecasts for the past produced with a model configuration that is as close as possible to the operational system. They are used to define thresholds and for forecast evaluation. Both seasonal and shorter-range reforecasts are produced.


All datasets are updated after a major operational system upgrade and are given a new version number.</dct:abstract>
        <dcat:theme rdf:resource="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu:443//geonetwork/thesaurus/GEMET%20-%20INSPIRE%20themes%2C%20version%201.0/Atmospheric conditions"/>
        <dcat:theme rdf:resource="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu:443//geonetwork/thesaurus/Climate%20Data%20Store%20facets/Provider: Copernicus CEMS"/>
        <dcat:theme rdf:resource="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu:443//geonetwork/thesaurus/iso/topicCategory/climatologyMeteorologyAtmosphere"/>
        <foaf:thumbnail rdf:resource="https://datastore.copernicus-climate.eu/c3s/published-forms-v2/c3sprod/provider-cems-without/overview.jpg"/>
        <dct:spatial>
          <ogc:Polygon xmlns:ogc="http://www.opengis.net/rdf#">
            <ogc:asWKT rdf:datatype="http://www.opengis.net/rdf#WKTLiteral">&lt;http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/OGC/1.3/CRS84&gt;
            Polygon((0 -89, 0 89, 360 89, 360 -89, 0 -89))</ogc:asWKT>
          </ogc:Polygon>
        </dct:spatial>
        <dct:temporal>1900-01-01
          /
          3000-01-01</dct:temporal>
        <dct:publisher rdf:resource="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu:443//geonetwork/organization/ECMWF"/>
        <dct:accrualPeriodicity>asNeeded</dct:accrualPeriodicity>
        <dct:language>eng</dct:language>
        <dct:license>licence</dct:license>
        <dct:license>https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/api/v2/terms/static/provider-without.pdf</dct:license>
        <dcat:distribution rdf:resource="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/cdsapp#!/dataset/eu.copernicus.climate.provider-cems-without"/>
        <dcat:dataQuality>EC Copernicus program</dcat:dataQuality>
      </dcat:Dataset>
    </rdf:RDF>
    