<csw:Record xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EO:EUM:DAT:0407</dc:identifier>
      <dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">OLCI Level 2 Ocean Colour Full Resolution - Sentinel-3</dc:title>
      <dc:type xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">series</dc:type>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ocean</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ocean Colour</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Level 2 Data</dc:subject>
      <dct:modified xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2023-05-31</dct:modified>
      <dct:abstract xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">OLCI (Ocean and Land Colour Instrument) Ocean Colour Geophysical Products. Full Resolution: 300m at nadir. All Sentinel-3 NRT products are available at pick-up point in less than 3h. Level 2 marine products include the following: * water-leaving reflectances in 16 bands, Oa**_reflectance (Baseline Atmospheric Correction (BAC) algorithm, bands: 400, 412, 442, 490, 510, 560, 620, 665, 674, 681, 709, 754, 779, 865, 885, 1024 nanometer (nm)); *algal pigment concentration in clear waters, chl_oc4me (BAC and maximum band ratio algorithm, log10 scaled); *algal pigment concentration in turbid waters, chl_nn (neural net algorithm, log10 scaled); *total suspended matter concentration, tsm_nn (neural net algorithm, log10 scaled); *diffuse attenuation coefficient Kd of downward irradiance at 490 nm, trsp (BAC and M07 algorithm, log10 scaled); *absorption coefficient at 443 nm of coloured detrital and dissolved organic matter, iop_nn (neural net algorithm, log10 scaled); *instantaneous photosynthetically active radiation, PAR (BAC and clear-sky ocean algorithm); *aerosol optical thickness T865 and aerosol Angstrom exponent A865, w_aer (BAC algorithm, A for bands 779 and 865 nm) *integrated water vapour column, iwv (1D-Var algorithm). The geophysical products are accompanied by error estimate products. Pixel classification, quality and science flags, as well as meteorological, geometry and geolocation data at tie points are provided. 

- All Sentinel-3 NRT products are available at pick-up point in less than 3h
- All Sentinel-3 Non Time Critical (NTC) products are available at pick-up point in less than 30 days
Sentinel-3 is part of a series of Sentinel satellites, under the umbrella of the EU Copernicus programme.</dct:abstract>
      <dc:coverage xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Global</dc:coverage>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">-</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">copyright</dc:rights>
      <dct:accessRights xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">copyright</dct:accessRights>
      <dct:created xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2017-07-05</dct:created>
      <ows:BoundingBox xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows">
        <ows:LowerCorner>-180.0 -90.0</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>180.0 90.0</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
    </csw:Record>
    