<csw:Record xmlns:csw="http://www.opengis.net/cat/csw/2.0.2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
      <dc:identifier xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EO:EUM:DAT:METOP:ASCSZF1B</dc:identifier>
      <dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">ASCAT Level 1 Sigma0 Full Resolution - Metop - Global</dc:title>
      <dc:type xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">series</dc:type>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ocean</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Radar Backscatter NRCS</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Level 1 Data</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Land</dc:subject>
      <dct:modified xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2022-05-11</dct:modified>
      <dct:abstract xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">The prime objective of the Advanced SCATterometer (ASCAT) is to measure wind speed and direction over the oceans, and the main operational application is the assimilation of ocean winds in NWP models. Other operational applications, based on the use of measurements of the backscattering coefficient, are sea ice edge detection and monitoring, monitoring sea ice, snow cover, soil moisture and surface parameters. This product consists of geo-located radar backscatter values along the six ASCAT beams. The different beam measurements are not collocated into a regular swath grid and the individual measurements are not spatially averaged. The resolution of each of the 255 backscatter values per each beam varies slightly along the beam, but it is approximately 10km (in the along beam direction) x 25 km (across the beam). This product is usually referred to as 'ASCAT Level 1B Full resolution product'. Note that some of the data are reprocessed. Please refer to the associated product validation reports or product release notes for further information.


Metop-A data are available in the Data Centre up to 15/11/2021.</dct:abstract>
      <dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2010-09-21</dc:date>
      <dc:coverage xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Global</dc:coverage>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">CWIC</dc:rights>
      <dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">license</dc:rights>
      <dct:accessRights xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">license</dct:accessRights>
      <dct:alternative xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">ASCSZF1B</dct:alternative>
      <dct:created xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2009-03-23</dct:created>
      <ows:BoundingBox xmlns:ows="http://www.opengis.net/ows">
        <ows:LowerCorner>-180.0 -90.0</ows:LowerCorner>
        <ows:UpperCorner>180.0 90.0</ows:UpperCorner>
      </ows:BoundingBox>
    </csw:Record>
    